So shall we start, Swami?
Today we are celebrating Guru Purnima.
See, Guru is nothing but to remove our ignorance.
See, Lord Datta, He is the Guru Datta.
He always comes, incarnate Himself to remove our ignorance.
And our beloved Sri Ratna Swami is incarnation of Lord Datta
and came down in human form to give excellent knowledge and remove our ignorance
and showing in, taking us in a right direction and a right path.
And we know in spirituality we have lot of questions
and lot of twisted knowledge was also there.
And Swami is correlated all the spiritual knowledge.
Like today we are saying Guru Purnima is Vedavyaasa birthday.
Our Swami is correlated even all the Vedas, Upanishads and Bhagavad Gita, Prasthana Trayam.
Not only that He correlated even the modern science up to this point.
Swami is giving excellent spiritual knowledge.
Only He incarnate to remove our ignorance.
Datta Swami is none other than the Lord Datta Himself.
And we are so fortunate that today directly we are meeting,
we are talking, we are seeing our contemporary human incarnation.
It's so fortune that we can directly get all clarifications, all our doubts.
He will clear all our doubts.
If everybody can ask whatever they got doubts, Swami will clear all our doubts.
I pray Swami please remove our ignorance and give your blessings to all of us.
So anybody have questions can ask, can question Swami, Swami can answer all the questions.
Shall I ask? Yes, yes.
Aadha Namaskaram Swami, this is Bharat Krishna.
Swami my question is generally it is said that it will take millions of janmas to achieve the spiritual goal
which is to please God that is the human incarnation of God.
Why it takes so much time Swami?
See, in Bhagavad Gita there is one verse,
Adha Chayaram Nichchayatam Nishcham Vamanyaseyamrutam.
That means this soul, this individual soul dies in the night in deep sleep.
And in the morning when you awake he is reborn.
So one day in one life.
So many births means many days, not years, not lives, not even years.
Just one day morning he is born, night he dies in deep sleep.
Therefore if you take the right interpretation it means only after many days only you can get the salvation.
That's all.
Here the question is why it takes so much time?
In Bhagavad Gita the verse says that this soul dies in deep sleep every night.
And in the morning when you wake up he is reborn.
So one day in one life.
So many births means many days.
So there is no need to worry about it.
Thank you Swami, excellent.
Swami ji, I have one question.
With respect to having expectation of the fruit of a work that has been performed,
should not be there to avoid tension.
But how can a work be done without having an intention of doing it for a particular fruit?
That I am not able to understand.
So you see, you can have intention for some fruit.
You are working for it. To achieve the fruit you are doing work.
That much initial intention is alright.
But during the entire course of work if you always think about the fruit only,
then your energy will be exhausted in thinking about the fruit and energy is limited always.
And that limited energy is spent in thinking about the fruit in the excitational way.
Then there will be no energy to do the work.
Then you will not get the fruit.
Initially you can have some fixation of fruit.
Later on you should not think about the fruit.
If you go on thinking due to attraction towards fruit,
if you go on thinking and worrying about the fruit,
all your energy will be spent in that worry, in that excitation,
in thinking about the fruit only, then energy will be over.
Energy is limited.
Then energy is not remaining to do the work.
You will stop doing work in the middle itself.
And if the work is not completed, you will not get the fruit.
Therefore you should not worry about the fruit.
Once you start the work, you should not worry about the fruit.
What he is asking is,
we should not think about the fruits,
we should go on working.
How can we do the work if we do not think about the fruits?
The answer to that is,
we are working for the fruit.
There is no wrong in deciding this at first.
But if you think about the fruit while working,
being worry about the fruit,
being excited while thinking about the fruit,
with this, your energy will be spent.
Then energy and power will not be there.
Power will not work for you.
Therefore, if you do not think about the fruit,
you will not get the fruit.
If you work completely, you will get the fruit.
Therefore, if you do not think about the fruit,
you should not be excited while thinking about it.
If you are thinking about it, you cannot do the work.
That is the meaning of it.
Thank you, Swamiji.
Namaste.
Can I ask a question?
Yes.
Swamiji, without any mistakes,
someone cheated on us.
How do we take care of that person?
Without our mistakes,
people cheat on us.
How do we think about it?
Is it our karma that that person has given us
to teach us some lessons?
You see, if you want to escape cheating,
you should have precaution.
Prevention is better than cure.
Okay, already somebody cheated
and you underwent some loss.
Now, the next method is
to take care in the future.
Take it as a lesson.
First, if you go to the background,
it is only due to past karma.
You might have cheated that fellow
in the past birth,
and now he is cheating you.
So that is a retarded case,
mutual canceling.
So you cannot take action on him again.
If it is a retarded case,
you cannot do anything against that.
If it is a fresh case,
you have not cheated him in the previous birth.
Freshly he has cheated you now in this birth.
In that case, you leave to God
and don't have any revenge attitude, vengeance.
Don't show vengeance.
Keep silent and leave to God and pray to God.
If it is a fresh case,
God will certainly punish him, not only punish him.
See, if he is punished,
your loss will not be compensated.
So you should not think about his punishment.
Punishing him, punishment means to reform him.
By punishment,
God is going to reform that sinner.
It is only for reformation,
not for vengeance, not for revenge.
Even if he is punished,
how your vengeance goes,
your loss is lost, your loss is not compensated.
What do you get by punishing him?
Nothing you will get.
Your loss is there.
So when you are thinking with revenge,
vengeance attitude,
your health is spoiled.
Previous loss plus more loss.
So therefore, don't develop any revenge attitude.
Keep silent, pray to God,
and leave the result to God.
Now God will certainly take action
because the case is now in the court of God.
God is the ruler of this entire world on any day.
If the revenge is not taken,
if the fellow is not punished,
it is a black mark on the administration of God.
He is more worried.
Why should you worry about his administration?
Moreover, if he is punished,
you are not getting your loss compensated.
Moreover, another third point is
that if you show revenge, vengeance attitude,
on that fellow, what happens?
For your revenge attitude,
he will be also punished by God.
God will punish him,
but extra, he will be also punished for your revengeful attitude.
Best example, you know Draupadi,
injustice was done to Draupadi.
The Kauravas dragged her shari and tried to make her naked.
So Kauravas are sinners.
Draupadi is the victim.
Kauravas are the criminals.
God has decided to punish Kauravas.
But meanwhile,
Draupadi showed lot of revenge attitude towards Kauravas.
She was always weeping and crying and telling Bhima and Arjuna
that unless you kill Dushyasana,
bring blood, I will not fold my hair.
Like that, she was always expressing vengeance,
revenge attitude towards the sinners.
Anyway, for the sin of Kauravas,
Kauravas were killed by Krishna.
Arjuna and Pandavas are only just nominal people.
Actually, the killer is only Krishna.
Krishna killed Kauravas.
And, since Draupadi was always showing
vengeance, revenge attitude,
what happened, you know, in the last day,
all the five sons of Draupadi were also killed by Yashoda Thama.
What is the use of winning the war?
If she wins the war,
her sons shall become the kings.
Then only it has meaning.
So along with Kauravas, her five sons were killed
and no son of Draupadi became the king.
The kingdom which was won by the war.
So therefore, if it is a retarded case,
if you have cheated him in the previous birth,
now he has cheated, cancelled.
No more punishment for the criminal.
If it is not a retarded case, if it is a fresh case,
that is you have not cheated him in the previous birth,
but now he has cheated you,
okay, then also, you don't show
any revenge attitude towards your enemy.
You just pray God,
asking Him to do whatever He feels resisted.
Whatever is to be done, you please do.
You leave everything to God and pray God.
Then God will give you compensation for your loss,
plus God will punish them.
But God will punish them not for revenge,
your revenge or He has no revenge.
He punishes them only for reformation,
to reform the criminal.
That is the aim of punishment.
And moreover, if He is punished,
and if God is not compensating your loss,
what is the use of punishing your criminals?
What compensation you got?
You got no compensation.
So by punishing your enemy, you will not get any compensation.
So don't think of punishing your enemy.
Leave it to God.
God will punish your enemy and will also,
because you did not show any revenge attitude,
He will compensate your loss.
That is the real benefit.
Otherwise, if you show the attitude of vengeance,
what happens?
Your enemy will be punished,
if it is not a retort case,
but you will not be compensated by God.
And by punishing your enemy, did you get compensation?
Nothing.
So wisdom wise people,
what they do, they never make any revengeful attitude.
They will never show revengeful attitude.
They keep silent, leaving everything to the hands of God.
This is your administration.
You do whatever you want to do.
It is the administration of God.
If that fellow is really a criminal,
and if that criminal is not punished,
the black mark will come to God.
Because it is God's administration that is going on everywhere.
Not these governments which are present.
These are all superficial governments.
But the actual final judgment is given by God,
and things will happen as per that judgment.
So that is the best thing.
I will tell you in Telugu.
It is a good one.
Someone cheated me.
What should I do?
Should I fight the cheaters?
Or should I sit quietly?
That is the question he asked.
What I am saying is,
this could have been a retort case.
In the previous life, you might have cheated him.
He cheated you in this life.
We thought it was a retort case.
You cannot punish him.
Because the cheats you did and his cheats, both were cancelled.
So there should be no further action.
You cannot do anything to him also.
There is no proof for that.
You might be feeling sad then.
The second thing is that it could have been a fresh case.
You did not cheat him.
But he cheated you in this life.
If you cheat him in a fresh way,
you should be angry and scold him.
You should be angry and scold him.
You might be feeling sad.
The question you should ask is,
if you punish him,
will your loss be fulfilled?
Will your loss be compensated?
It will not be.
What is your profit if he punishes you?
So, will he escape without punishing him?
He will escape.
You have no profit because he punished you.
You have no loss because he punished you.
So, you should think about it.
You should decide
what you should do.
You should leave it to God.
You should leave it to God and pray to God for your peace.
Not for his loss.
You should pray to God for your peace.
You should leave it to God.
God is the King of Kings.
He is the final.
All these are the government.
The underlying government
is God's government.
Jesus Christ says,
My father is a kingdom of the universe.
The kingdom of the universe is the government of God.
So, that is the stable.
That is the actual mediterranean.
It is the final.
If you leave it to God,
what will God do? He will punish you.
Why will he punish you?
He will not punish you with a knife.
He will punish you to change his mind.
He will punish you for reformation.
That is why he punishes you.
He punishes you if you are not a man.
If you scold him,
he will cancel your punishment.
So, God punishes you.
He will delay your punishment.
He will give you time to think about the change.
He will punish you and change you temporarily.
Punishment will be completed.
Punishment is not to teach you a lesson.
Punishment is to change you.
You can say,
I am not useful even if I get punished.
God will punish you
for being peaceful,
for being a teacher to God,
for not showing your anger,
for being peaceful,
God will make you suffer.
If you are like this,
this is the story of Draupadi.
She was killed by the Christians.
They died because of the Christians.
One day, Arjuna asked Yashodh,
one of the Drona's disciples,
Yashodh came to Siva and said,
Grandfather,
when I fight,
I use arrows,
but when I use arrows,
before my arrow hits him,
I take a great sage, Trishula, and kill him.
After he dies, my arrow hits him.
Who is that great sage?
Then the Drona said,
You have done penance for Pashupatastra,
and I will tell you that
the sage is killing your enemies.
I will tell you that the sage is killing your enemies.
That is why
God will punish them.
He will definitely punish them.
You will not be able to fight because of the punishment.
I am talking about Draupadi.
Draupadi was insulted.
He decided to kill the Drona,
but he killed him.
He was so angry that he decided to kill him.
The sage killed the Drona
and the sage killed the Drona.
He was in a state of peace
because he could not keep his mouth shut.
He killed five of his children.
He was in a state of peace
because he could not keep his mouth shut.
Why did he want to fight?
He wanted to make his children kings.
What happened to the children?
All the children died.
So, that's how your mouth is punished.
So, your mouth is a district.
You should stop and be calm.
This is the kingdom of Bhagavan.
This is the administration of Bhagavan.
If the person who has done wrong to you is not punished,
then the next black mark will come to Bhagavan.
Why will it come to you?
Right?
It will come to Bhagavan.
He will stop and tell the black mark.
He is really worried.
He should be worried, not you.
You are the one who is fighting for his administration and his black mark.
You should fight for him.
Right?
So, when you stop and fight for his administration,
you should stop and fight for Bhagavan.
You should stop and fight for him.
I would have cheated him in the past life.
He would have cheated me in the future life.
It has been cancelled.
You should stop and fight for him.
You should stop and fight for Bhagavan.
Why is the black mark coming to him?
You are not getting anything.
You are staying calm.
He is coming with the black mark.
That is why he is not quiet.
He will punish.
Even in that punishment,
he did not do it for vengeance,
but for revenge.
For reformation.
To change his mind.
He is punishing to change his behavior.
You are asking for punishment,
but not to change his behavior.
You are going to be in trouble.
You are also different from Bhagavan.
You are not the one who is not punished.
You are asking for punishment,
but not to change your behavior.
He is not able to punish,
but he will punish,
but he will not speak.
He is punishing to change his behavior.
He is also punishing to help.
That is why he is doing it.
He is not quiet.
So, the reason is,
because you are staying calm,
because you are not asking for punishment,
because you are not asking for revenge,
he will compensate for your loss.
He will punish you.
He is also punishing.
Now, tell me what is the benefit.
Another thing,
he is punishing to shout.
You are also being punished.
Did you hear what he said?
He is punishing to shout.
He is also punishing to shout.
Why?
Because he is not talking.
He is talking.
Because he is not talking,
he is being punished.
He is being punished.
He is being punished
because he is not being compensated.
He is being punished.
That is the duty of a God.
It is a duty of a God
to punish the one who sins,
Questioner 1 – Swamiji, you have reached the small stars, Swamiji.
Swamiji – I have not reached them.
Swamiji – I have reached the small stars, Swamiji.
Okay, let me do everything.
Okay.
Swamiji, human incarnation of God is compared to sugar and devotee is compared as ant.
Ramakrishna.
Swamiji, in other context, even a prostitute also can be compared as sugar and the vitlu...
Prostitute is like sugar, it can be compared to ears, it can be compared to sex.
Syphilis, Gneria, it can be compared to ears also.
What is your doubt?
Even in prostitution, even they sing good songs to God.
Now, I am saying that Gopikas were sages in previous births.
So, now in their last birth, they are offering their body to God.
In the same in Nivruthi case, if a prostitute wants to get liberation,
why should she use the money she got when she was in that prostitute's body?
Why should she not get liberated?
See, someone behind me killed a war.
He killed a war and made a sin,
he cut his skin, hit him with a shovel and offered his body to God.
The sin is going away.
He killed a war, cut his skin, hit him with a shovel and offered his body to God.
Oh, my! My child is gone.
In fact, prostitution is a sin.
In prostitution, the sin is to get a good life.
I am singing songs to God, I am offering my body to God.
I am a sinner.
I am offering my body to God.
If I give the money I earned to God, it is not a sin.
We should earn according to our religion.
According to our religion, our family members are also being exploited.
They come up.
This is how the word of injustice is.
The war of injustice is a war of co-existence.
You earned 10 rupees in a fair way.
You earned a quarter of a rupee unjustly.
The money is linked to the 10 rupees.
Railways have a platform.
The railway engine is linked to everything.
The whole platform is linked to the money.
The money earned unjustly is linked to the 10 rupees.
You earned 10 rupees unjustly.
I earned two quarters of a rupee unjustly.
You earned a quarter of a rupee unjustly.
The money earned according to religion is linked to the 10 rupees.
The railway engine is linked to everything.
The money earned in the previous religion is linked to everything.
The money is linked to everything.
Every single thing is being exploited.
Why do we earn?
Because we are in the middle of the world.
That is the only desire.
It does not work.
They are being exploited.
Every single thing.
The money gained unjustly will only be exploited once the money is there.
They are in the middle of the world.
It does not work.
If you give it to the Lord, let us assume that the Lord will always save it, accept it.
When the Lord will always save it, accept it, from then on you will be unjust.
You will realize repentance and non-repentance.
If these three come together, it is reformation.
We know that this is a sin.
Realization.
Repentance.
You will feel sad that you have sinned.
Non-repentance.
You should not repeat the sin again in your life.
Then these sins and the sins done in the past will be completely cancelled.
Completely cancelled.
If you do these three.
Some people do realization, repentance and non-repetition.
The sin done in the morning is forgiven in the evening.
The sin done in the night is forgiven in the morning.
The sin done in the morning is forgiven in the morning.
Now I am free.
I will sin again in the morning.
Then I will forgive in the evening.
It is not forgotten.
It is not red.
Red is coming and washing it.
It is free.
It is pure.
That is the principle.
It works.
Non-repetition of the sin.
Realization.
You realized that this is a sin.
You repented for it.
You should not repeat it again.
After these three.
Not only that sin.
The sins done in the past.
Everything is forgiven.
The best Vedic.
Everything.
The sins done in the past.
Not all sins.
That type of sins.
You committed theft.
You realized.
You did non-repetition without committing theft.
The thefts done in the past will be cancelled.
But the other types of sins.
The other types.
If you do non-repetition of that type.
That file will be cancelled.
If you do not do any sin.
That will be cancelled.
So that is the knowledge.
The best of the best.
That is.
The non-repetition.
Not to repeat.
In life.
When you realize that.
The whole process will be completed.
But what are they doing?
They are realizing.
They are repenting.
Confession.
The sin committed in the past.
Confession in the past.
That is not the reason.
It will not be cancelled.
Confession will not cancel the sin.
Non-repetition.
They will not repeat it.
If they repeat it.
All the sins will be cancelled.
Not only this sin.
Because.
The logic is.
All the sins are being cancelled.
What is the purpose of sin?
Reformation.
When you come to that reformation.
Why do you do more sin?
When you have already done.
It is not necessary to do more sin.
That is the logic.
Punishment is only for reformation.
And punishment is not for vengeance.
And punishment is not for revenge.
Punishment is not for revenge.
Punishment is to get reformation.
He killed one.
He is doing more sin.
Do you know why?
Because he is not killing the second person.
Suppose he is really killing the second person.
What is the purpose of his more sin?
Why do you do more sin?
Because it is waste.
That is the logic.
Okay?
Namaste Swamiji.
Namaste.
I am Adiv Mandal here from Mumbai.
Yes, yes, yes.
Tell me.
On this auspicious
Guru Gurudwara Nima day,
I offer my sincere gratitude
and a total prostrated pranam
to your divine lotus feet.
Okay, thank you.
And to my appeal,
regarding my weak and
unrest mind, you have said
that I assured you,
you will succeed in getting your problem cured.
Your words came true
in all aspects of my mental health.
Later, recently
on my query on my better health condition,
you have said,
you will get my guidance
as you proceed in the work.
But I also wanted
to go in the direction of God,
which is a permanent solution.
And there, you have also said,
you will have to face
a lot of strain in working
for God.
Kindly elaborate further on this,
as I am ready to go to any extent
to prove that I could come
close to you, Swamiji,
in my life.
Okay, very good.
You are blessed.
Thank you, Swamiji.
You will get a proper
guidance.
You need not do
too much work also, you need not do.
You can do as per your
health permits,
as per your capacity permits,
as per your energy permits.
That is sufficient
for God. Whether you are interested
in doing practical work
for my case or not,
that is only the test of God.
He is not in need of
any work from us.
If there is any need,
then the fellow will
think, if he does more work,
my work will be bored
and all done. Not like that.
God is only testing
whether you are
only theoretical or practical.
Also,
practical is the proof
for theory.
Practical devotion is
the proof for theoretical devotion.
Theoretical devotion
without practical devotion
is false
love.
It is not true love.
Unless you sacrifice something practically,
unless you do
some service practically,
service means
sacrifice of energy,
physical energy.
Sacrifice of
fruit of work.
That is, first is
Karma Sanyasa, another is Karma
Phalakshayaga. Both these together
are called as Karma Yoga.
Karma Yoga is
the proof for Bhakti Yoga.
Bhakti Yoga is
theoretical devotion.
Karma Yoga is practical devotion.
Practical devotion is the
proof for the truth
of theoretical devotion.
Whether your
Bhakti is real or false,
that Karma Yoga decides.
The practical devotion decides.
Otherwise, simply
gas.
You sing so many songs,
shed tears,
then God will say,
He will also sing songs on you,
He will also shed tears,
or if you want a boon
for that, oh,
you get more sweeter voice,
He will let you get more tears
from your eyes.
So for theoretical
devotion, theoretical boon.
For practical devotion, practical boon.
So actually in our India,
we are very, very much
very, highly
experts in theoretical
devotion.
That is why once
somebody asked, Swami
Vivekananda looked at this guy
and asked God,
why in our country,
in India, so much devotion,
so much knowledge is there,
but still why they are poor?
Somebody has put that question to me, directed that question
to me. Then I told,
yes, our India
is very great in
knowledge, spiritual knowledge, Gnana Yoga.
And experts
in Bhakti Yoga,
singing songs on God,
but will not give
a single rupee for a poor fellow.
In practical devotion,
they are zero.
In foreign countries,
they are
least Gnana Yoga, very least
Bhakti Yoga, but they do charity,
practical charity they do much.
That is why they are rich countries,
our country is poor country.
That is the reason.
We are experts in theoretical
devotion, theoretical knowledge.
So for theoretical knowledge
and theoretical devotion, God gave
theoretical boons. Let your
knowledge increase more, let your
brain become more intelligent,
let your voice become more
sweet, let more tears
come while you sing songs,
let your audience also
shed tears,
more tears.
So theoretical devotion
means theoretical boons.
Ye yadhamam prapadyante
tamstadhaiva bhajanyam
In whatever way you approach
me, I approach
ye gaiyim by the same way.
If you come by bus,
I will come by bus.
If you come by train, I will come by train.
If you come by aeroplane, I will come by aeroplane.
In Veda also it is told,
rupam rupam prithu rupam bhuvah
I am just your reflection,
your mirror reflection.
Whatever you,
in whatever way you approach,
if you show your intelligence,
I will show a lot of intelligence.
It will give you
a lot of fruit.
If you show innocence,
I will be also innocent.
Herod has asked
that he should not be killed by
such, such things, such things,
either day or night, or inside or outside,
or weapons with
awareness or without awareness,
like that, so many conditions.
All the conditions
he has broken.
And for every condition he neutralized.
And killed Hirayana Vishnu.
He should not be,
he should not belong to a single race,
man or animal
or Deva or Asura,
Gandharva,
Narasimha.
Neither man nor animal.
Neither inside nor outside,
at the center of the gate.
It is neither outside nor inside.
Nor on the floor, nor on the sky.
He has put on his laps.
It is neither floor nor on the sky.
Like that, for every thing he has
shown me, God is the exception.
He is very intelligent.
You show your intelligence
to other human beings.
But when you come before
God, kindly shut
up your intelligence.
Be innocent.
Be frank with him.
Don't show
your intelligence.
If he enters into the game,
your address will not be there.
So don't play with him.
Be frank.
Be sincere.
Be truthful.
Then you will get something from him.
If you show intelligence,
you are finished.
So you see Sudama,
how innocent he is.
He gave three handfuls
of pastured rice.
Did not ask anything.
He came back to his house.
He never thought
about anything
returned from him.
And when he came back to his house,
unimaginable
wealth he gave.
Because he is innocent.
See, his
wife sent him to Krishna
to get something.
He was so poor.
But that fellow did not
speak anything.
Krishna asked him to stay for four days.
He stayed four days.
Then he told, I will go to my
home. Yes,
go. Like that he told.
He did not give any
one rupee.
You know when he was washing his feet
when he came,
there was a thorn
in his feet.
He was not
having the sensitivity of that thorn.
He was not having any
chappals to his
feet. So when he
came and when he was washing,
all his eight wives were pouring
water and he was washing
his feet. And that thorn
hit his
palm.
Then he plucked
out.
From that time
onwards,
there is no need
of the eight wives to pour water
with gold vessels.
Because
he washed his feet
with the water of his eyes.
From that time onwards,
he washed his feet with his
tears.
Water was not necessary.
Satchakrishna,
he doesn't
have any chappals.
Now he is going back to his home.
Hey, Sudama,
wait. At least take this ten
rupees. Purchase some second-hand
chappal.
He should give it or not?
No, not a single rupee he gave.
He also
started again working with that bare
foot, feet.
And
as long as
he was going to his house,
Krishna, he had the miraculous powers.
He is observing the mind of
Sudama. Whether
somewhere, that fellow,
he has wept
seeing my feet while
washing the feet.
And when I am coming,
one rupee he has not given.
He acted like
Hollywood hero.
Acting?
Unseen matter.
Now one rupee he has not given.
Like that, whether he will
stay in his mind, he was observing
his mind.
He has capacity, you know.
Omnipotent, omnipotent.
Till
he went near to his house,
the house remained like
that only.
Just when he is approaching his
house, he bent his head and
he is approaching his house.
Then suddenly, now he will not
scold Krishna. He decided
Krishna. At that
moment, he changed his
thinking. The house became a
big palace.
It was not turned immediately.
He waited
till he reached in the house,
whether he will scold me once or not.
If he had his
scolder once, his house will remain
like that also.
Any question?
Swamiji, Namaskaram Swamiji.
Few minutes back you answered
about not having the revengeable
attitude when someone cheats us.
So, let us take one example.
If someone cheats me by stealing some money,
so, if I
file a complaint in police,
is that also a revengeable attitude
or is it justified? No, that is not
a revengeable attitude because
you don't know whether it is a retarded case
or a fresh case.
Okay?
So, there
when I have taken the case of
Draupadi,
that situation is completely different.
She cannot fight by filing
case in court
because it was
the king, Guryasana was the king.
Is it not?
So,
what I tell
is the case,
the circumstances
in which
you cannot do anything,
any reaction, you cannot, you are unable
to take any reaction.
Very big fellow.
You cannot fight with him.
Similarly, you see compare
Draupadi and Duryodhana.
They are very powerful.
She is lady.
She cannot fight.
So, that
circumstances are like that.
If there is anything
to be that you can do,
you do it. But sometimes,
that fellow may be very big
rowdy. He may
say, if you go to police station or
court, you will be finished.
Then you will not go.
Then what to do?
Okay?
One more question.
That same question,
Swamiji.
But we will be having
like a pain or like hurt
like that person has did
these things with me.
So, we were very suffering from
those pain, not that
person who has done
cheating and all.
See, if you can
fight, you fight out.
If you are cheated by somebody
and if there is provision for you to
fight, you fight.
That is not wrong.
Suppose,
there is no provision to fight.
Suppose, that fellow is
very powerful.
You are not so much powerful. Suppose, he
says, if you fight, I will kill you.
And we are encouraged also, you found
that he is capable of doing
that.
In those circumstances, I told
like this.
But if you are able to fight
it,
and you are not
fighting, you are sitting like Arjuna in the
Kurukshetra war,
what Krishna told to Arjuna?
You fight.
See, you have got some army,
they have got some army,
he came to the war
to fight,
then you fight.
He did not say,
go, go back.
Everything
throw on God and keep
silent.
He did not
tell like that.
Hello?
Ok?
See, if you have
provision to fight, if you have
chance to fight, you must fight.
If there is no such provision,
if the enemy is very strong,
and suppose
threatens that he will kill you,
and on enquiry he also
found that he is capable
of such things,
then you
approach God.
Not about me, then
what about then in relations
kind of, like how
where we can fight,
like if that person did
this with us, then?
What relation you mean?
See, when he has cheated
you, when he has
cheated you, what type of
relationship you can have with him?
No relation.
You should cut off all your relations.
He is a cheat.
He has cheated you.
If you maintain
another relationship, he will again cheat you.
See,
when you are cooking
the food rice, you take
one grain
and press it, whether it is
cooked or not. Is it not?
So, one
example is sufficient.
The entire rice is
represented by that one grain.
His entire life is represented
by that one example.
That is one example.
Padanamaskaram Swami.
Is wanting liberation
an act of aspiration, though it is
not worldly? As long as
God is a fruit at the end,
you would be aspiring to reach Him.
So, how should we approach God, Swami?
A new history.
So, is wanting
liberation an act of
aspiration, though it is not worldly?
As long as God is the fruit
at the end, we would be aspiring
to reach Him. So, how
should we approach God, Swami?
See, you are talking
about liberation
and reaching
God.
Is it not?
Attachment to God
and detachment from liberation
means detachment from
worldly bonds.
Detachment from worldly
and attachment to God.
Here they are very much related.
Unless you attach to God, you cannot liberate yourself from the variety.
If you want to have some detachment from something, you must attach yourself to some other thing.
Then the detachment will be spontaneous.
Automatically you will be detached.
Suppose you are sitting in the cinema hall, seeing the cinema, you are very much absorbed
in the cinema.
You are very much attached to the cinema story.
Now the mosquitoes are biting.
The blood bugs of the seat, they are also biting.
You need not try to liberate from mosquitoes and blood bugs.
If you are absorbed in that cinema, you will not mind these bites.
You are automatically liberated.
So the attachment to God must be the cause for your detachment from the world.
Without attachment to God, if you liberate from the world, it is the biggest foolishness.
You see, I am drinking divine nectar, amrutam.
I am drinking it.
Then spontaneously, automatically, I want to drink coffee.
Before the taste of amrutam, this is nothing.
I hate it.
I don't take it.
Because of the taste of amrutam.
Neither you drink amrutam, nor you drink coffee.
You are a fool.
At least if amrutam is not available, let me drink coffee.
Something I have to drink.
That drinking habit is there for this tongue and for the mind.
The mind always wants to drink something.
The mind always wants to attach itself to something.
That is its inherent nature.
So now you are not attaching yourself to God.
You are also not attaching yourself to the world.
Will the mind keep silent?
In two or three days, you will have double attachment to the world.
It is not a prerequisite.
To drink divine nectar, there is no precondition that you should not drink coffee.
It is not a pre-stipulated condition.
If you drink divine nectar, due to that taste, you automatically, spontaneously leave drinking
coffee.
Such type of detachment you should get.
Without drinking divine nectar, you want to leave the coffee.
Two days, three days you will leave.
On fourth day you will drink a bucket of coffee.
It is impossible.
Detachment from the world without attachment to God is impossible and also foolish and
also useless.
What is the use?
At least if that is not available, you enjoy this.
You leave this.
You don't enjoy that.
Then you will not be able to enjoy the world.
So, Moksha, liberation from the worldly bonds, is defined as the liberation from the worldly
bonds due to the attachment to God.
That is very important.
First you must attach to God.
Then you should not try for liberation from worldly bonds.
Automatically it takes place.
It is spontaneous.
It is a spontaneous by-product.
For which you need to try at all.
It is a natural phenomenon.
Naturally you will get detachment.
You drink divine nectar.
Naturally you will be detached from coffee.
Such a type of liberation is Moksha.
You are not drinking divine nectar.
You are not attached to God.
You are leaving the worldly bonds.
That is not Moksha at all.
It is only foolishness.
People leave the house and go to forest.
They will come and sit there in meditation.
They will be thinking only worldly things.
Then they will run back.
They will come back to home.
They will not come back.
They will run.
Run back.
Run back to the home.
Understand?
Swamiji, I have a question regarding food burning in rituals.
So what I personally saw, there are three rituals that I want to explain.
One is in the 10th ritual.
They put the rice in a mud pot and they put some kowdung in it.
Raw rice and put kowdung in it.
They take the dead body along with that pot and cremate it.
Regarding that one death ritual Swamiji.
The other one is with the tarpanam.
Kanda Rishan Tarpanam and the Pudhra Pudhra.
They have black sesame seeds and raw rice mixed.
We put in water and we do tarpanam.
That rice and seeds should be thrown in a place where it can't be grown back.
That instruction has been given by elders at my home.
The third one is having a haven for Samitha Dhanam, for Brahmacharis who have completed
Upanayanam.
After every Sandhya Mandhanam, Samitha Dhanam is also instructed for Brahmacharis.
These three rituals, clarifications I need Swamiji.
You see, there is one shloka in Dharmasastra in the scripture itself.
When there is a contradiction between Smruti and Shruti Veda.
You should take only Shruti as the authority, not the Smruti.
And these traditions which are suggested, these traditions do not have Adharadi, Shruti
or Smruti.
They just say that our forefathers did like this.
Only Purnachara, Purva Tari Kurta.
Their strength is only, it was practised by our ancestors.
So there are now three types of Adharadhis.
One is Veda Adharadi, another is Brahmachastra Adharadi and another is Achara Adharadi.
This Achara has the least strength.
Shruti is greater than Smruti.
Smruti is greater than Achara.
Now, when a thing is presented to Smruti, what Smruti says is,
Annam napadhyat shedata gurakam.
You should not waste food under any circumstances.
It is a vratam.
Gurakan means it is very hard, fast food.
It is very serious food.
That is what Veda says.
Annam napadhyat shedata gurakam.
The food shall not be wasted at any cost.
That is told by Shruti.
Now even if you bring some Adharadhi from the secondary scriptures, that is Smruti, Dharmashastras,
it cannot stand.
Because it is not protected to Shruti.
Now you are bringing Adharadhi from Achara, tradition.
Our forefathers did like that.
So my father told like this to do.
That has least weakest authority.
That cannot be Adharadhi because you know Prahalada, he was born in the Demons.
The traditional Achara is to abuse Vishnu.
And to worship Shiva in the Demons.
That was the Adharadhi, Achara authority.
Did Prahalada follow it?
He didn't follow because Achara authority is the least.
Somebody in the beginning might have added and that error might have been carried by
several generations.
So therefore all your three examples are contradicted or ruled out by Veda.
Which says Annam na parichachita.
Parichachita means, Pari means completely.
Chachita means destroy.
You should not destroy the food.
Pari means completely.
Even a trace of food you shall not destroy.
Even when you are eating the food, the plate from which you ate the food, the plate should
be as clean as before serving the meals.
Before serving the meals the plate is clean.
Similarly the plate should be clean after you are eating.
That is the meaning of this Vedic statement.
And Veda cannot be contradicted even by Dharma Shastras.
Even Smruti cannot contradict Veda.
If there is a contradiction Smruti shall be left and you should follow only Veda.
That is what Dharma Shastra itself says.
Shruti Smruti Virodhetu Shruti Virodhetu.
Veda is the highest authority.
So all the examples given by you must not be practised at any cost because it is Vedic
authority.
Ok?
Ok Swamiji.
Right.
But you don't quarrel with your parents and all these people.
At least it will be your marriage is over.
Otherwise you will enter into problems.
Ok Swamiji.
My name is Ravinder Reddy.
Swami, is there any pre-plan for human beings birth?
Does the karma occur in the life as it is from previous life?
Is there any change in karma implementation in the human life?
Can we escape from karma?
There are so many questions if you ask.
I cannot remember one by one you ask.
Ok Swami.
Swami, is there any pre-plan for human beings birth?
Pre-plan can be there.
Everybody has pre-plan.
If you want to do something you plan.
You want to build a house.
You have taken the plan first.
Is it not?
Pre-planning is an inevitable step for any activity of human being.
Does the karma occur in the life as it is from previous life?
Does the?
What do you mean by that?
Tell me.
What does it mean?
Does the karma occur in the life as it is from previous life?
Yes.
See, the rule is,
the rule is,
when a person dies by leaving this world,
he goes to heaven and hell.
He experiences all the good karmas in heaven.
He experiences all the bad karmas in hell.
So, all karmas are over, right?
How can he be born?
He should be born after the end of the karma, right?
When you experience these karmas,
there is a trace of karma left.
Because,
when you are taught, you should take a complete mark.
Otherwise, you cannot give complete encouragement when you are rewarded.
You are rewarded in heaven.
For the good karma you have done.
For the bad karma you have done, you are taught.
For example, if you see the situation in hell,
if you take a complete mark,
you cannot take 100% of it.
If you take 99% of it,
you will get 1% of it left.
If you steal something,
you will be tortured to a third degree in the police station.
If you give it,
he will not be punished for a few days.
But, after a few days,
he will get along with his friends and steal again.
Because, punishment should always be given in a complete reformation.
Only spiritual knowledge.
As Sadguru said,
only spiritual knowledge will give complete reformation.
So,
how will you be punished for bad karmas in hell?
The police station will give you a punishment for stealing.
There is no difference in that.
Even if he is tortured to a third degree,
after he comes out,
he will be doing nothing for a few months.
But, when he is punished for stealing,
there will be a seed inside.
It will not get burnt completely.
There will be only a seed left.
When the seed is burnt,
the seed will be burnt again after a long time.
So, there will be a seed left.
So, in the olden days,
there is a connection between the karmas we do now and the ones we do now.
Due to punishment,
the entire karma should be destroyed.
Only a little bit of karma will remain.
Because, punishment is not the whole karma.
Punishment should be given in a complete reformation.
Only spiritual knowledge should be given in a complete reformation.
So, due to that,
the karma will remain in the soul.
The karma will be affected by that.
The new life will come to the soul.
If the karma is zero,
the new life will not come again.
For what purpose?
For the new life.
There is no karma.
So, due to the karma,
the new life will come to the soul.
After karma,
karma will not be the karma,
but the karma will be in the form of a body.
Karma is doing what is called as lying.
The lie is in the form of a body.
The body remains in the form of a body.
The body can be called as karma.
The body is a thought.
The thought is done with the energy of nervousness.
The action is done with physical energy.
We are talking about a place,
physical energy.
There is a thought,
that thought is nervous energy.
Both are energies.
But the weakest is very powerful.
Because of the weakness,
thoughts are not taught in the narkam.
If you think of an evil thought,
it will not teach you practicality.
I will call you and give you a warning.
You have done a thought.
Don't touch it.
After doing that thought,
the action will be done.
Practicality will be taught.
I will give you a warning.
Because,
if the thought is practically implemented,
then there will be a crime.
But, nobody is affected by the thought.
Only you are affected.
You should not have sleep.
It doesn't affect others.
So, if there is a wrong thought in you,
you will not be practically punished in the end.
But, you will be warned severely.
That is there.
I say, a thought is very dangerous.
If that thought increases,
it will render into action.
So, you should not be afraid.
You must cut it by thought itself.
In the stage of thought itself.
So, there is a relationship between
past karma and present karmas.
Because, the past karma in the form of
quality thought,
exists in the jiva.
And that provokes to do
further actions.
So, there is a relationship between
samaskara, vasana.
There is nothing but a very subtle form of karma.
So, that provokes to do
fresh actions in this.
So, there is a relationship.
Namaskaram Swamiji.
Swamiji, reformation means there is no quality.
Reformation means there is no quality.
Talk about the soul of the queen.
In Dravapati case,
Arjun will bring Aswadam.
After her children died,
then Aswadam's
teacher, a son,
her mother is crying
and they ask her to leave her.
Then, she will be reformed.
Why did you talk about her?
She was theoretically,
she was practically converted
to kill.
She was provoking her husband
to do the war,
to kill Kavaravas.
Every day she was telling them.
That is why they were very much provoked.
Her theory
resulted in the practice
of her husband.
So, she is responsible practically.
As the Lord now told,
thought you should not neglect thought.
The thought, by further concentration,
will lead you to action.
Swami ji, you told that
liberation means attachment to the God
and through attachment of the God only
we can aim from the world.
Means through devotion like
singing songs and doing Japa, Tabai
whatever we are doing,
by the grace of you
you do whatever you want.
You attach to God
either by songs or by knowledge
or by practical devotion.
Whatever you do, whatever suits to you
you do. But the result is there.
The result decides the action.
Once we stop
whatever Japa or knowledge order
the worldly life like Maya
is 200% strong.
You change the method.
There are so many alternative methods
to attach to God.
Whatever suits to your psychology
you select that method.
You have to try all the methods.
Sometimes all the methods
may have partial influence
but all partial influences added
may be the total influence.
By using all the methods you may attach to God.
Though each method
is influencing you partially only
but when you use all methods
all partial influences added
becomes the total influence.
Or some method alone may
influence you. Other methods may not influence you at all.
Then select that method only.
See different souls are there
with different psychological,
with different mental setups.
So whatever suits to a specific mental setup
you select that.
It may be one method or two methods or three methods
or may be all methods.
That you have to select.
Questioner- Namaskaram Swami.
Swami today on Guru Poornima
today morning I have seen
Lakshman garu donating 5 lakh rupees
and JSR Prasad garu donating 2 lakh rupees
to Swami and you also told that
Swamiji- How you came to know? I did not open the cheques.
I saw Swamiji. Swamiji- We have opened the cheques for you.
I have seen that.
Swamiji- Open the cheques.
I saw Swami. Swamiji- Open the cheques folded.
Sharma Sir showed me Swami.
I don't know.
They gave folded cheques.
I just kept there folded cheques.
I don't know. I have seen there on the table Swami.
Swamiji- I shall pay you tax? No.
There is one officer
Lakshman's wife.
She is income tax assistant commissioner.
So she will ask what
fourth floor you were holding.
Swamiji- No. Sorry Swami.
But you also told that karma phala tyaga is the highest.
And more than karma sanyasa
also karma phala tyaga is the highest.
Now
can I say that I should invest more time
in getting a better job and higher job so that
I can earn more and also I can sacrifice more.
Yes. Correct.
I am telling it is not the
question of the value
of the donated item.
God sees. See when
Jesus was sitting in church, several rich people came.
And donated hundreds, thousands of coins.
One fellow donated hundred coins, another fellow
donated two hundred coins, one fellow donated thousand
coins. Like that. Is it not?
One beggar donated only one
coin. Jesus immediately
arose and told
she is the best donor.
She, her donation is the best
donation. Because
the percentage of the donated item in the
possession of total wealth
that is seen by God.
She donated one coin. She don't have
any more coin. So her sacrifice is
hundred percent.
Swamiji- Sorry Swami.
Sorry Swami.
So her donation
he rose from the chair and told
that this is the best donor.
She is the best
devotee.
So these people, one fellow might have donated
thousand coins. He might have donated one lakh
coins. So one thousand by one lakh.
That is the percentage of sacrifice.
That gives the value.
So God doesn't
see, but if you go to a
businessman, if you give ten rupees
he will give one fourth kilo of
time. If you give twenty rupees
he will give half kilo of time. He is
seeing the value of the
given item.
That is business devotion.
But God what he sees
whether the sacrifice, what is the
he has donated thousand coins.
Thousand coins, how much he got?
What is the fraction of this thousand
in the total possessed by him?
Is it not?
So who donated best?
Only that one coin donor is the best.
Not the thousand
coins. Is it not?
Sudama donated only three handful
porcelain rice. That also
he took on loan
from neighbors. When he returned back
Krishna did not give him the porcelain rice.
He did not return.
Now he is coming home, he has to clear the
loan.
And he did not criticize Krishna
in mind.
Something marvelous.
So he gave unimaginable
wealth to him. Unimaginable.
Actually he gave
three handful quantities of
rice. Krishna took only two handful
quantities. Third quantity when he was going to
eat, Rukmini caught. Because if he
eats the third quantity, Krishna will become
Sudama, Kuchera. All the wealth of
Krishna. He wanted to give all his wealth to Sudama.
So he
you see people may think
that God can be purchased
by money.
That is the karma phalatyaaga is not
God can be purchased by money.
Karma phalatyaaga is a proof
of theoretical devotion.
Karma phalatyaaga must be done as a proof
It is very clear in the
world of science also.
Suppose a boy loves a girl.
Theoretically loving, singing songs,
praising her, all like that.
See he should spend
something from his pocket.
Then only she will develop some
confidence.
Otherwise after marriage also, this fellow
will not give food. Simply he will go on
praising me.
Even if
All the things it is proved.
See, in Telugu there is a saying,
raaka poka lunti bandhutva,
petti posisthe aapetchanu.
Aapetchanu means real love, true love.
Petti posisthe, if you do practical sacrifice,
then aapetchanu, petti posisthe aapetchanu.
Aapetchanu is prema, real love.
If there is real love, he will stand something in your pocket.
That is true in pravrti.
You need not go upto nimruti.
Even in pravrti it is proved.
Okay?
So that here, you may say,
no, I don't have that much money,
only little, I have 100 rupees only.
Now I will earn 1000 rupees and give to God.
Is God in need of your 1000 rupees?
Or 100 rupees?
If you give now 100 rupees, your sacrifice is 100 percent.
Tomorrow when you give, out of 1000, you give 900 rupees,
it is not 100 percent sacrifice.
Today by 100 rupees, donating 100 rupees, your sacrifice is 100 percent.
Tomorrow when you see 1000,
last time I gave 100, why should I give 1000?
Okay, 200 I will give, this time.
You will not give 1000.
Once you get more money, you develop more attachment to money.
Since your income was less, your attachment was less.
That is why you could give 100 rupees.
If you get more money, ambition for money also increases.
Attachment to money also increases.
That is why rich people can never donate.
Only poor people can donate.
Always in this test, poor people succeeded.
No rich man succeeded.
When Adi Shankara went to the lady house, she was very poor.
Nothing was there.
She searched all the houses.
One small fruit was found.
That small fruit she brought and put in the vessel of Adi Shankara.
Then Adi Shankara was so much pleased.
Everyday he is going for begging.
People are giving some food, some vegetables, something.
But he was not so much pleased.
But this lady, not having anything in the house to eat,
they were fasting for 10 days.
And he searched in the house.
One small fruit was found.
That fruit she brought.
Instead of fasting for 10 days,
at least that fruit if she eats, some energy will come.
Some citrus fruit.
Amarka fruit.
But she gave to Adi Shankara.
Then seeing that, he told Kankathaara stotra.
And golden fruits were rained by Goddess Sarjiv.
Why this lady was so much blessed?
Other days he was going to several houses.
They are giving some food, some vegetables, some garlands.
They are giving him his lesser.
He did not.
So this is Goddess Sarjiv.
Whatever they are giving is far far more greater than this small fruit.
Here why he blessed her with rain of golden fruits?
Because her sacrifice is 100% sacrifice.
Nothing is there.
Whatever she had, she gave whole.
That is 100% sacrifice.
But other houses they gave some food.
Rest of the food?
The percentage sacrifice was only 1% or 0.5% or 0.1%.
But here 100% sacrifice.
So in Ramakesha I say 200% sacrifice.
Because he had nothing in the house.
He went to the neighbors and brought a load to give Krishna.
If this lady's sacrifice is 100%, his sacrifice is 200%.
On load he brought.
Will everybody give on load?
If I have I will give something.
Or maximum devotion.
Whatever I have I will give.
That is the maximum, limit.
No, even if I don't have, I will go to other houses, beg for load.
And then what is the percentage calculates?
Can anybody calculate the percentage?
Swamiji, load on the gating by your grace only also.
That is the, see that should be a secret.
That should not be opened.
If that is opened, you see I told you one story.
Grandfather bought and brought a biscuit packet.
To his house, the grandson was there.
He gave the packet to the daughter-in-law, that is the mother of the grandson.
And told her not to reveal that I bought this packet.
Keep it secret.
Then she took one biscuit and gave to the child, boy.
Now grandfather, she did not tell that grandfather bought these biscuits.
Now the grandfather went to the child, grandson.
I am feeling hungry.
Give a part of that biscuit.
He asked the grandson.
Suppose grandson knows that grandfather bought the biscuit packet.
He will immediately give all the biscuits to him.
He will also go to mother and give some three or four biscuits.
I will give to my grandfather.
Because he brought all the biscuits.
He bought 100 biscuits.
Why one biscuit?
Some three or four biscuits he will give.
But that is not true love.
That is only expression of gratefulness.
He has given.
I gave him little.
That is only business.
To and fro.
It is not.
So that is why he asked the daughter-in-law to keep it secret.
Don't tell that I brought his biscuits.
Now I am asking the biscuits.
If he has true love on me, he will give that biscuit to me.
Then he has true love on me.
That should not be open.
If it is kept a secret, then only the test will be properly done.
Otherwise the gratefulness factor will lengthen.
He will automatically give me biscuits.
He has brought for me 100 biscuits.
Can't I give one biscuit to him?
That is not true love.
He has not brought biscuits to me.
My mother only purchased these biscuits.
But he is my grandfather.
He is asking why not I give this biscuit.
That is the true love.
He came to test my true love.
Not gratefulness.
So to test my true love, that should be kept secret.
He brought all his biscuits.
That should be kept secret.
He is giving everybody.
Everything, anything, anybody has, is given only by God.
Everybody knows it.
That should not be, that should not strike his mind in this test.
While testing he hides that also.
It will not strike your mind.
Suppose it strikes your mind.
Suppose he is God.
Let me give.
Then by his power of Maya, you will start doubting.
Is this fellow God?
Who is begging?
Are you this guy?
He will create Maya.
You will find out that.
Because the true gratefulness is not the test.
The true love, which is different from gratefulness.
Of course people, nowadays people don't have even that gratefulness.
That is a different thing.
But the real seriousness of the test will be spoiled.
The truth is always here.
Then only the real test can take place.
Swami, I have a question.
Nowadays the, moreover society is divided based on the caste and religion.
And as a Sadguru you should unite all the people.
How you can unite all the people based on the caste and religion?
If I stand for elections, I will unite all the castes and afterwards.
In fact I am trying.
First I tried to get sympathy from women.
So you are saying that Gayatri, women are actually doing Gayatri, not men.
And also that Egya is done by female soldiers.
Because Egya means cooking the food and giving to Vaishwara Ragini of the hungry people.
So that only they are doing.
This is not Egya.
That I have given a lot of arguments.
So I am slowly winning the votes of women first.
You know, 50%
Almost 50% votes.
Then I am also doing that.
You see even caste system.
I denied the caste system.
I did that work also.
That Gura Karma Vibhavishah.
Caste is not decided by birth.
Caste is decided by the qualities and the deeds.
Chaturvarna Maya Srishtam.
Guna Karma Vibhavishah.
Based on qualities and deeds.
The caste is decided.
I have given examples from Veda.
Sachakrama Jadhara.
He doesn't know the name of his father.
And the Gurukula Gautama asked her, who is your father?
I don't know.
I will ask my mother.
I am working in several houses.
I don't know who is your father.
Then that fellow came and told, proof only.
My mother tells that she doesn't know to whom I am born.
So I don't know my father's name.
He told the truth.
Then Gautama, that person who is admitting to the school.
Gautama.
He told, you must be a Brahmin.
Because you are telling the truth, you must be Brahmin.
Because you are Brahmin, you are telling the truth.
See, there is a difference.
Because you are telling the truth, whatever caste you may be born.
Because you are telling the truth, you are Brahmin.
He did not say, you must have been born in Brahmin family.
That is why you are telling the truth.
He did not say like this.
From the quality, I derive the caste.
Not from the caste I derive the quality.
I gave that example in my knowledge.
And also another one.
Janashwati.
Janashwati was born as a king.
He is a Kshatriya.
And says, Raikpa called him as Shudra.
Because he was always worried mentally.
Because here he knows the caste of Janashwati that he is Kshatriya.
At least in Sachikabha Javara's case, he doesn't know the caste of Sachikabha Javara.
Here in the case of Janashwati, he is a king, ruling king.
He is born in Kshatriya caste.
But since he is worried, he calls him Shudra.
The person who worries is Shudra.
That does not mean that a boy born in Shudra family will be worried.
That is the conclusion.
That cannot be concluded here because he knows Janashwati is a Kshatriya.
He is a king.
How can he have two castes?
I know what the caste of Janashwati is.
Now I am calling him Shudra because he is worried.
So from quality, the caste is derived.
Not from the caste quality is derived.
See, our people, you see,
Rommaharshan was a pot-maker.
Kumari.
And in Naimisha forest, when sages were doing,
big yajna was performed in Naimisha area.
Then all the sages made this Rommaharshana as the head of the sacrifice.
This pot-maker.
All these are brahmana sages.
But they made the head of the sacrifice, this Rommaharshana,
who is a pot-maker, Kumari,
he is made the head.
Then Balarama came.
All stood.
But this Rommaharshana did not stand.
Because the rule is, the head of the sacrifice shall not stand for anybody.
So that rule he followed.
Then Balarama became angry.
Why these all brahmana sages are standing?
This fellow is pot-maker.
He is not standing, seeing me.
He took the halayas and killed him.
Then all sages scolded Balarama.
In Bhagavatam it is there.
Scolded Balarama.
Even though he is pot-maker, by his knowledge of Vedas,
by his parents, by his qualities,
he is not only brahmana, he is the best brahmana.
That is why he was made the president of the sacrifice.
You have done wrong thing.
All sages condemned Balarama.
Then Balarama being the incarnation of Adi Shesha,
he gave life to him.
And asked an excuse, asked Rommaharshana to excuse his sin.
This is in Bhagavatam.
So, you see, all these nonsense was created
just 5000 years back since Kali age started.
Because Kali wants to split the people.
Quarrel with each other.
Kali, Kali is like this.
The characteristics of Kali is only to split,
create quarrels, create hatred.
So that I have taken lot of care about these things in my knowledge.
What is time?
5 o'clock.
Swami, I have got a question.
Yes.
Swami, the proof of the practical devotion is
karma phalachyaga and karma sanjyaga.
So between these two, which one is higher?
See, in Gita it is clearly told that karma phalachyaga is the highest.
See, scientifically also explained.
In karma sanyasa, in doing sacrifice of work,
energy is sacrificed.
In karma phalachyaga, sacrifice of matter is there.
Money, matter.
Gold, in those days gold, gems, they are the wealth.
Not these rupee notes.
Rupee coins, gold coins.
So between energy and matter,
what is the relationship E is equal to MC square?
That means lot of energy is equal to small matter.
Small amount of matter is equal to lot of energy.
So which is more valuable?
Matter is valuable.
If that small matter is converted to energy,
lot of energy, atom bomb, what is there?
Small one nucleus is broken, how much energy it is releasing?
So, energy, matter, matter is greater than energy, scientifically.
And this point is, can be, the answer for this point,
can be found in pravrutti itself.
You need not go to nivrutti field.
Even in our ordinary pravrutti, it is found.
It can be found.
So, see employer-employee relationship.
Employee is sacrificing energy, work.
Employer is giving money, matter.
Who is respecting whom?
Employee is respecting the employer.
Employer who gives matter, employee who gives energy.
There are several people to do the sacrifice of energy.
Employers are several people are there.
But employers are very less.
Employment is very less.
Is it time?
So, keep it all this one side.
Another side is, in pravrutti itself, you can say,
somebody is a, he is a very rich man.
Here the question of capability is there.
See when it is done, yadha shakti, yadha bhakti.
As per your capability and as per your devotion,
whichever is lesser.
So, in calculating HRA, they do four rules.
Whichever is the least, for that is the tax.
You know it.
Similarly, here suppose you have capability of 100 rupees.
You can donate 100 rupees to me.
You have got that capability.
But I am such a nasty fellow,
your impression on me is only 10 rupees.
This fellow deserves 10 rupees.
More than 10 rupees he doesn't deserve.
You have capacity of 100 rupees.
But your impression on me, that is bhakti,
your shakti is 100, but your bhakti on me is only 10.
Between 100 and 10, which is the minimum?
10 rupees only you should give to me.
And suppose it is reverse.
Your capacity is 10, but your impression on me is to give 100.
Even though you have impression to give me 100,
but you don't have capability.
You have only 10 rupees in your pocket.
Your capacity is that only.
Then which is minimum?
Then only 10 rupees.
Suppose your capacity and shakti and bhakti are equal,
your capacity is 100, your devotion on me also is 100, you 100.
Suppose your capacity is 10 and your impression on me also is 10,
you can both donate.
Four possibilities.
Is it not?
So that is the meaning of
yadha shakti, yadha bhakti,
tubhyamaham, dachshinam, samparare namamaam.
Yadha shakti, yadha bhakti has these four probabilities.
You take these four probabilities, you can understand.
Is it not?
Padanamaskaram Swami.
And some exceptional rules, exceptional examples are there.
Satuprastha is an exceptional example.
In a drawer, he got some floor.
After one month of fasting,
he, his wife, his son and the daughter of the four members,
some floor was obtained after one month of fasting.
He cooked it, they cooked it,
and they brought four leaves,
and four parts they divided, each one shared.
Then Satuprastha came,
the guest, the guest.
He asked for some food.
Then that Satuprastha,
he gave his share to him.
He ate.
I am hungry still.
Then his wife gave her share.
The son gave his share.
I am hungry still.
The daughter gave her share.
All the four parts he took.
That is an exceptional case.
That is entire 100% fact.
Just now I told you, Jesus' case.
That dagger.
One rupee.
One rupee, one coin.
So that these are special exceptional examples.
Exceptional examples.
So therefore, what is the question?
Which is greater?
See, it is the question of capability.
Suppose somebody is a multimillionaire.
He comes to me,
sits here with lot of devotion,
goes on pressing my feet.
Doesn't he want to eat?
He is capable.
That is very important.
If he is not capable,
even if he gives one paisa,
that is 100% fact.
He is capable multimillionaire.
Because he is multimillionaire,
he cares even for one paisa.
If he is a poor man,
he won't care even for 100 rupees note.
As he becomes rich,
the greediness increases.
That is why, even if he gives more,
the percentage is less only.
So therefore, here,
if he is capable of doing Karmasanyasa,
and does only Karmasanyasa,
that example we have to take.
That example will reveal the truth.
If he is not capable of donating, giving Guru Laksana,
he is only capable of doing Karmasanyasa,
in that case, that Karmasanyasa is 100% sacrament.
Whatever he can sacrifice, he will sacrifice it.
That is why it is called Karmasanyasa.
Done to be done by saints.
Saints cannot do Karmaphalakshara.
Because he himself is begging for food.
What Karmaphalakshara he can do?
So, it is called, that Sanyasa word is put in that, Karmasanyasa.
Actually, the principle behind is that,
the Karmaphalakshara is a test for the theoretical devotion.
I am not going to Dhuruti, I am not going to spiritual life.
I am talking in Dhuruti itself,
what is life itself?
You are capable of spending,
and you don't spend a rupee on me,
how can I marry you?
She will ask.
And her argument is correct.
If you are poor, you are not able to spend on me, I agree.
That is not all.
You are not greedy.
Now you are not spending.
But you have lot, but doesn't spend a rupee on me.
There the question comes.
Capacity.
So, this answer for this can be easily found out
in Purodhvarayana life itself.
You need not come up to spiritual life.
It is a very common example,
very common concept, even for Purodhvarayana life.
There you must add one thing.
You are thinking only Karmaphalakshara.
Karmaphalakshara, provided he is capable of doing this.
That is the point.
This is Shakti, this is Bhakti.
As per his capacity, and as per his devotion,
which are his minimum?
HR is minimum.
Which are his minimum?
Yes.
If your capacity is 100,
but your impression on me is only 10,
then Bhootham.
Shakti is 100, but Bhakti is only 10.
Minimum is 10.
Shakti is 10, but Bhakti is 100.
Then also minimum 10.
If your Shakti is 100 and Bhakti is 100,
you both are tallied.
So you will give 100.
If your Shakti is 10 and Bhakti is also 10,
then 10 minimum.
Both tallied.
That is what major temple, ordinary source.
Exceptional devotees it is different.
Like Sudama, Satuprastha,
they are exceptional devotees.
Or that lady who gave that fruit,
Amalaka fruit,
Tuazhi Shankara,
they are all exceptional.
You cannot take them as examples.
I have one more question regarding...
She told that
that Latshwant gave 5 lakhs,
and J.S.R. Prasad gave 2 lakhs.
You know how many lakhs she gave?
14 lakhs she gave.
She gave 14 lakhs.
And she is telling,
you are giving 2 lakhs,
what about this?
He is very cunning.
Swami, I have a question.
Swami, Krishna told that Gunakarma is a part of Bhagavad Gita
and you are also condemning that Kali Yuga is not following the rule of Krishna
regarding the classification of caste.
As per now, since 5000 years, actually society is suffering from wrong classification of caste system.
But at present it is not suffering. Government rule, as per the government rule, that is changing.
Gunakarma Yuhasah is now the rule of the government.
It's not so. I don't see that, Swami.
No, no, no. In fact, the lower caste are giving the reservations.
Yes, Swami. That is what the problem is.
So, it is like the problem is, Swami.
Reservations is the problem.
But that is based on Bartholino, Swami.
That is based on Bartholino.
Based on Bartholino, they are classified as reservation.
But that is, deciding caste based on Barth, that wrong tradition came from the beginning of Kali Yuga.
So it is still persisting.
At least based on that, now the bad tradition that started from the beginning of Kali Yuga,
that is not present in the present government.
Because you are born in upper caste, jobs will be given.
That is not there. Because you are born in lower caste, you will be job.
That is the government policy.
Is it not?
But your rule is not being followed, no?
My rule will never be followed.
Because these rules which I have told, they have only told theoretical, not practical.
See, my rule, whatever I told is the correct rule.
Let it reach to all the people.
Let them think.
Let them debate.
In future we are expecting.
Padna Maspara, Swami.
Yes.
Swami ji, I have one question regarding Karmapalli Tyaga Swami ji.
Swami ji, just now for a previous question, you told gratefulness to God and love towards God.
They are two different things.
Yes.
Gratefulness is a seamless devotion.
See, you have given 10 rupees to the shopkeeper.
He has given 1 fourth kilo of tamarind to you.
There is something like business.
That is, since you have given 10 rupees, the seller can say that since you have given me 10 rupees,
to express my gratitude, I have treated your 10 rupees as your donation to me, to my shop.
Now as gratefulness, I am giving 1 fourth kilo of tamarind to you.
See, it suits the business.
Even if you express in different language, the basic business is suited.
You can say like that there, in the business devotion.
But what is the real love?
Somebody comes and doesn't give any rupee, you give 1 kilo of tamarind to him.
That is one way traffic.
It is not two way traffic.
Two way traffic is business.
And one way traffic is real love.
True love is always one way traffic.
You don't expect anything from the other side.
Since you have true real love on him or her, you are giving your donating.
You are not expecting anything in return for your donation.
You have real love on him and his personality and his qualities.
Whatever may be the reason, you have developed some real love.
And hence you are donating.
You are expressing your love in practical form.
Karma Yoga.
That is true karma phalakshya.
Or you are doing some work for him.
That is true karma sanyasa.
You are not expecting anything in return from him.
Then you don't aspire any fruit in return from God.
Then that is true love.
You see, two-fac...
Fan devotion, you have read it?
My fan devotion?
NTR is the actor.
There is some fan.
Whenever his cinema is released, he is spending from his pocket.
Nothing, no fruit.
The hero doesn't know even his name.
He is not giving anything for this fellow.
And this fellow is not expecting anything from that hero.
Since he has developed a fascination towards his personality that is projected in the cinemas,
he appears very good, very good person in the cinemas.
Though he is very rude outside.
Projected false personality.
But he is seeing and he is impressed.
Based on that projected personality,
he develops a real love on that personality.
And he is spending from his pocket.
For all the inauguration functions of his new pictures.
And moreover, when he dies,
his family members are taking that dead body to the burial ground and burning it.
Coming to home,
coming to home and take all the property arranged by him.
This fan did not take a single paisa from that hero.
Even the money he has spent from his pocket,
that was also not paid by that hero.
But when he died, this fellow is burning himself.
Doing suicide.
What a marvelous love it is.
Fan devotion.
See I divided the devotion into four types.
Prostitution devotion, business devotion, issue devotion, then fan devotion.
Issue devotion is also very good.
Issue devotion and fan devotion are pure love.
Parents. Parents are giving all their property to the children.
See when the parents become old,
the son is putting the bed in the Varanlal.
You are coughing all night.
Then the parents are scolding him.
You fellow, we have served you from childhood.
Now since your wife came, you have forgotten us.
Like that they scold him.
They scold him, but they don't change the name of their son.
That is also pure love.
Parents love their children.
That is called issue devotion.
Issue will change.
Then next is fan devotion.
Fan devotion is climax devotion.
So there without any aspiration in return,
the true love is shown.
When there is aspiration in return,
and there is exchange from both sides,
it is true love traffic,
then it is business devotion.
And the first prostitution devotion,
that is to a large extent in our country.
If you want a job, that is a practical boon from God.
Read 108 times Hanuman Chalisa.
This is to get devotion.
Nothing 10 paisa he has not spent.
108 times Hanuman Chalisa, 11 times Vistu Sasana.
Give me a job.
Give me Lathai.
Give me profit in my business.
For theoretical devotion, practical boon is the exchange.
Prostitution devotion.
What the prostitute is doing?
When her customers come,
she sings songs,
sheds tears, shows love,
all falls in love,
and takes his money.
Money is the practical.
All the songs is theoretical.
Exchange of practical boons for theoretical devotion.
That is Veshyabhakti.
And exchange of practical devotion with practical boons,
that is Vaishya Bhakti.
So prostitution devotion, business devotion,
issue devotion and fan devotion.
In issue devotion and fan devotion,
there is no aspiration for anything in return.
So issue devotion and fan devotion,
you must develop towards God.
But how we will develop it?
When we want to go to a temple,
some issue will come to our mind.
Some variety of block books will come to our mind.
Some variety of benefits will come to our mind.
Then you will go to temple.
There we will do practical devotion also.
But for the sake of variety of benefits,
or solution for the variety of problems.
If you are doing practical devotion,
to get some practical benefit from God,
that is Vaishya Bhakti, business devotion,
exchange of practical things
for another practical thing.
10 rupees, 1 fourth kilo tamarind.
Both are materials.
Material exchange.
But this, I will sing songs,
giving money.
Theoretical devotion, exchange is for practical boons.
These two are not correct.
Only issue devotion
and fan devotion.
Actually, God Datta, you see,
parents show issue devotion towards issues,
towards their children.
And what God Datta did,
I am Datta, Datta Putra, I am your son.
So she also showed me the devotion,
issue devotion, because I am Datta.
Datta means Datta Putra.
Our people, what they thought, you know,
if we treat him as Datta Putra,
then in issue devotion,
the parents must give to the son.
Then immediately they changed the plate.
Tomeva mātāśa pīṭhā tomeva.
We are your children.
I am your child.
You are my father and mother.
So give, a reverse.
Then God Datta became mad.
And Tomeva became the one.
She didn't tell it so.
Immediately reverse.
No, no, no, you are not the one Datta Putra.
Datta itself means Datta Putra.
The adopted son is called as Datta.
Auraśa Putra means born,
biologically born.
Purusriva Putra,
by artificial,
no, test tube baby,
that is called as Purusriva Putra.
Then Gūrhatpanna,
that is by secretly the wife,
by artificial insemination.
Gūrhatpanna,
Chetrajana,
then Datta, there are ten types of sons.
Out of that, Datta is one name.
Datta means adopted son.
Adopted son also will ask for property.
At least some property.
Nothing to do with that.
Danger for us,
loss for us,
and profit to God.
No, Swamiji, no.
Tomeva Mata is a prithatma.
You are both mother and father.
They thought that if I am mother and some father,
then there may be some problems.
He is alone, Datta.
So you are mother and father.
So just let give yourself.
Ashtanga Namaskaram, Swamiji.
You told about sacrifice, right?
Sacrificing 100%,
with the ambition that God will take care
if something happens in the future.
No, no, sacrifice 100%,
he is for an exceptional devotee.
Are you exceptional devotee?
Are you one of the public?
Or not?
You are one of the public.
Then Adha Shakti, Adha Bhakti.
You must save your family.
Your family expenditure.
Your expenditure.
You see, one thing I am telling you.
If the aim of your life is
to serve God,
then the amount you earn
and save for your expenses,
the amount you earn and save
for the expenses of your family,
wife and children,
all these expenses
can be put in the account of God.
So, you must save your family.
All these expenses,
which you are earning
and spending on you and your family,
they can be credited
to the account of God.
That means, all these expenses
are donated to God.
Why?
Suppose your aim,
life's aim is
to serve God.
For serving God,
you must maintain yourself.
You must be able to
serve God. You must maintain yourself.
And for having good health
and all that, you must have
a home, some family,
wife, etc.
parents.
So, you have to maintain them.
You are maintaining yourself.
You are maintaining your family
for the happiness, so that
the ultimate aim of the life
is only to serve God.
Then all these
maintenance expenses
come under the account of God
and you have donated that to God.
You have spent from that for God.
There is a reality
in what I say.
There is no cheating, no cunning,
no cheating. Is it not true?
Unless you maintain
your body, unless you maintain
some peace of mind and happiness
of your mind,
how can you serve God?
So, all the expenses,
family expenses, expenses
spent on you,
they all come under
the God's account
and all that amount, totally
you have sacrificed, 100%
sacrificed in that. Only you have done.
Provided you keep
the aim of the life
and God.
Not worry.
Just by that one small thing,
you are getting the
effect of the same.
No, here also my logic is
my aim is to serve God only.
Not to serve the variant.
But to serve God,
shall I maintain my body or not?
I am maintaining my body only
to serve God.
I am not maintaining my body for my self-pleasure.
I am not maintaining
my body to enjoy worldly pleasures.
That is not my aim.
My aim is only I am
maintaining my body to serve God.
Then all my expenses,
right expenses.
All those expenses,
they come under the account
of God only.
They cannot be
personal expenses.
And
suppose I maintain, I spend
I take food and
see I must have some peace of mind.
If I marry, if there is
some wife, as soon as
evening I come to home,
she will take care of me.
If I become ill,
she will serve me.
Somebody is there
so that I will have peace of mind.
Not only health of the body,
but peace of mind must be also there.
In my old age,
my wife also will become old
and my children will be there too.
So I have to maintain them.
I have to maintain my wife,
my children,
for the sake of my mental peace.
Because I can serve God only
with full health
and also mental peace.
All this is only
for the sake, the final
aim is only to serve God.
All these expenses
come under the divine expenses,
spiritual expenses only.
Not worldly expenses.
Because my ultimate aim
is only to serve God.
I am not going to
serve God.
My intention
is important.
Intention decides the fruit.
Not the enough action.
I have told you
several examples.
Intention gives the fruit,
not the enough action.
I am doing the job, that is enough action.
I am earning,
that is enough.
My life aim is only to serve God.
So that I maintain
my health of body,
I maintain my peace of mind,
I take care of my old age,
so that I can serve God
in the old age also.
With peaceful mind.
So in that case,
when all your expenses
are diverted to God,
then you have done 100% sacrifice.
100% sacrifice you have done.
Because your ultimate aim is only to serve God.
Not for your worldly enjoyment.
All these facilities
only to give health to your body,
to give peace to your mind.
So that ultimately I can serve God.
These expenses come under
his account only.
Not your account,
personal account.
There is no personal account.
There is no personal aim to my life.
Except to serve God.
If that really you are having that intention,
not for the sake of expenses you develop.
Sincerity.
If you are sincere,
sincere,
you are a
devotee sacrifice 100%.
You are the sattu prastha.
You are sulama.
But you must have sincere.
You must be sincere. You must not play drama.
If you play drama,
if God starts playing
with us the game,
your address will not be there.
Always be sincere.
Be truthful.
Be innocent before God.
Don't show your intelligence.
Don't play with God.
Because you have so many
lack of nerves in your body.
Some intention, some ill thought
present in some nerve,
you may not be knowing that
God knows it.
So never
attempt to play
with God.
Be sincere.
So this is the best method for
the average person. You see,
everybody cannot become sulama.
Everybody cannot
become sattu prastha.
Is it not?
Then after all these expenses
are over, if something is left
over, you don't need to go.
If it is extra,
if it is not spent for this purpose.
That is what in
Latha Vedam I told.
I am not asking the
one rupee you spend for
your family expenditure.
I am not asking your one rupee
which you are saving for your old age.
I am asking
only your one rupee
which you are spending on your
luxuries,
getting your health spoiled.
Is it doing any profit to you?
No. Your health is spoiled.
Instead of that, stop luxuries.
You will be with good health.
You are benefited.
That one rupee you are spending
on luxuries, donate to me.
I am not giving you health there.
You yourself are protecting your health.
Oh God,
I have given this one rupee. God has
protected my health. You need nothing.
You have yourself protected
by controlling
your luxuries, wasting
money in luxuries.
I don't want the one rupee
you are spending on your expenses.
Latha Vedam.
I don't want the one rupee
you are saving for your old age.
You don't need
anything.
You don't need luxuries.
You put the one rupee
in your heart and donate it to me.
This actor is a great actor.
You put the one rupee in your heart and donate it to me.
How easy.
It is wealth
from waste. There is a project.
CSI project was there.
When I was doing my PhD,
that project was very famous.
Wealth from waste.
Here,
salvation from waste.
Wealth from waste is
pravruthi project.
I extend it to nivruthi.
Very easy method.
Beneficial method.
You are benefited.
You are protecting your health.
You are happy with your health.
Health is wealth.
If health is spoiled,
what is the use of wealth?
So many good schemes
are there.
You are laughing.
LIC schemes.
Dutta bank also.
Dutta bank.
Investment schemes.
See, I told about Dutta bank.
Once she asked,
Dutta bank,
whatever rupee
you are giving to me,
my assistant Karabhairava
will type it
and will put in Dutta bank.
So that whenever you need
in difficulties,
lot of interest
is added as the need.
Suppose you have given me
one rupee.
You needed one lakh.
I will give you one lakh.
As per the need.
Draupadi gave.
I will not personally use my hand.
I will see it.
Don't materialize it.
Not only that.
In this life,
you will be safe.
If you have got excess of money,
you will waste it
in unnecessary vices
and you will be in troubles.
This Karabhairava
will keep your one rupee
in my bank
and whenever you get
need in the next life,
even in the next life,
the needed amount will come to you.
Even in the next life,
there is no bank
to which you can say,
I am investing this,
next life I need.
Your address is not found
by the bank.
Like that I speak.
This is real life.
You must have real faith first.
Because you think me as a cheat.
You don't have faith on me.
And all these
things are useless.
First is confidence.
First is faith.
And moreover, Bhad Dutta does not need
anything from anybody.
He has enough wealth.
He can create wealth by his will.
Because these topics
come in pravrutti,
see,
Karma Sanyasa, Karma Falakshaka
are written in Gita.
I have not invented that.
Jnana Yoga, Bhakti Yoga and Karma Yoga.
Karma Yoga consists of Karma Sanyasa
Yoga and Karma Falakshaka.
Karma Sanyasa and Karma Falakshaka
together are called as Karma Yoga.
This is in Gita, Bhagavad Gita.
I have not invented.
I have not discovered.
And in Vela also
Dhane Nacchage Naike
Abhurat Tamaamashu
In Vela, it is in Gita.
And there are practical stories
like Sudhama,
Satuprastha.
There are practical stories in Puranas
related to these concepts.
So I am only defending
the scripture.
I have not invented
any concept.
Of course, I have invented
some concepts like Gayatri,
performance of Yajna
and Vedam is knowledge.
Mere recitation
is not the concept.
Like that, some concepts I have.
But this Karma Falakshaka
is clearly told
by Krishna.
So, Yohi Gnana
Vibhyasad
In the Vedas it is mentioned as Dhana Chyaga.
In Gita this Dhana Chyaga is reformed as Karma Phal Chyaga.
Dhana Chyaga means you may have some ancestral wealth.
You did not earn.
You don't have the money.
You may donate.
But if you have Karma Phala, hard earned money, I don't want this ancestral wealth.
I want from your Karma Phala.
Because you are more attached to your hard earned money than your ancestral money.
See God competes with the item with which you are most attached.
Whether you vote for that item or for me.
That is the Dattapariksha.
So there is hard earned money, Karma Phala.
And if you do Chyaga of that Karma Phala, that is the highest test.
After doing Karma Phala Chyaga, there is no effort left over on your side.
There is full stop.
Gnana Yoga, knowing the details of Mumbai city.
Then I developed anxiety and attraction towards Mumbai city.
To see that Mumbai city.
But the theoretical inspiration I developed is Bhakti Yoga.
Then third is Karma Yoga.
Karma Yoga, two steps.
Karma Sanyasa Yoga and Karma Phala Chyaga Yoga.
Karma Sanyasa Yoga, sacrifice of energy.
I walked up to the railway station, sacrificing my energy, physical energy.
That is Karma Sanyasa.
Then I purchased the ticket for Mumbai.
That is Karma Phala Chyaga.
I sat in the train.
What more effort I have to put to see Mumbai city?
So after Karma Phala Chyaga, there is nothing, no effort is left on your side.
Chyaga Shantiranantaram, full stop on your side.
So that is clearly written in Gita.
I must explain it.
Written in the scripture.
After all our names are same.
Krishna, Brahmanyam, Venugopal Krishna.
I must defend my name.
So I am only presenting the concepts written in Veda and Gita.
Not my own concept.
One question.
While doing Karma Phala Samarpanam to Sadhguru, why this justice should be considered?
Is really justice should be considered because you told that in farsabhaj it is a nibruti case.
Anything, there is a thorn.
When the thorn falls into the fire, it becomes vibhuti.
When there is such a case, why this justice should be considered?
That is, the thorn falls into the fire, right?
That is said in Gopika Maradhani.
Gopika, their illegal land, their derisional guard.
There are many such cases.
Kamopkantaka Gopika, Bhayamunam Kamsundu.
Several people have reached God in different ways.
And Gopika has reached God in a wrong way.
Which is also correct because you are...
For that I gave you that example.
Thorn is put in fire, it becomes sacred ash.
For that I told.
But it should be fine.
In the place of Krishna, if some other human being is there...
You are the Frenchman, are you?
No, everything you... Don't put on me.
This is the problem with you.
We are talking the concept.
We are discussing the logic of the concept.
Don't drag me.
Sorry.
So, the suppose Krishna is God.
Is it not?
Krishna is God.
For God there cannot be any wrong thing, you know.
Any injustice is not there in His sight.
No lust for God.
And who are the Gopikas?
They are sages.
For millions of births.
And who are the Gopikas?
They are sages.
For millions of births.
Doing penance for God.
Even when heavenly dancers like Rambha, Uroosh and Manaka came and danced with them.
They just cursed them.
They ran away.
Do they have lust?
No, they burn the lust.
They burn the lust.
And He is God who is not having the lust.
But Gopikas reach God through lust.
That is the point.
Neither this side lust is there, nor that side lust is there.
What is lust?
Lust is an action.
Kissing, hugging, all these are lust.
Inner actions.
What is intention in Gopikas?
Intention is not hormonal provoked lust.
Oh, Krishna is very beautiful.
So, let me enjoy Him.
Let me hug Him.
That is not the intention.
Krishna is God.
I have devotion.
Then they hug Him.
They kiss Him.
He is asking, what is that happening?
The hugging and kissing are inner actions.
And the background of that, the intention is devotion.
I give examples.
Father hugs and kisses his daughter.
It can be done.
What is that?
Mother can hug her son and kiss.
Brother can kiss his sister, his brother-in-law.
It is there in Ramayana.
When Rama returned back, she hugged her and kissed her.
That is in Varmiramayana.
So, this hugging and kissing is inner action.
But her intention is that she is her son.
What is the background?
Is there hormonal lust in Manas?
No.
Only love and son.
That is the background.
Suppose same hugging and kissing are done by a rowdy in the street.
Same hugging, same action.
But the intention is different.
He has some hormonal lust.
Here intention is different.
There intention is different.
The action is same.
That fellow is getting punishment in hell.
In court also.
This fellow is not getting punishment in court or in hell also.
Because his intention is different.
Not the inner action.
Inner action has no result.
The intention behind the action gives the fruit.
So, Govindanath hugged and kissed Krishna due to the devotion to God.
And a rowdy hugged and kissed some lady on the road with some hormonal lust.
That is the scene.
That is explained by Sage Narada.
They hugged and kissed Krishna knowing that he is God.
Thinking that he is God, they hugged him.
They know that Krishna is God.
The intention is devotion.
If the devotion is not there in the hearts of Godgast, that will be a crime.
The Godgast and Krishna both will be punished in hell.
These two sutras were written by Sage Narada as an explanation for this rasakali, ruchya, dance.
Gurudwara dance.
So that is there I told.
Because he is God, because they have devotion, even the thorn fell in the fire, it becomes a sacred ash.
That you cannot apply to everywhere in Puroorthi.
Suppose she is not a Godgast, she is not a sage, she is a hardly lady.
She is married, but she still hugged another human being with hormonal lust.
Will that example and this example will be same?
In that example, she will go to hell, he will go to hell.
And you know what is the punishment?
Red heart, copper statue, both will hug and kiss.
They will become ashes. Such high temperature.
So if Krishna is not God, if Gopikas are not sages, and if Gopikas did not hug with devotion to God, it will be an ordinary sin.
Both Krishna and Gopikas will go to hell.
That was clearly written by Sage Narada, Narada Bhakti Sattva.
That is ok Swamiji, but the thing is, if by the grace of you only we know that you are the God, then that time why not we...
You don't bring me into the discussion. You are talking about God, you talk about God.
Because you see, you may be thinking that I am God. You may be thinking, that is your opinion.
But it cannot be opinion of general. You have to respect the opinion of public and talk.
If you and I are all over there, you can talk as you like.
But you cannot talk your opinion when public is there.
Several times I told this to you. One day there, he told,
Swami, you came and suppressed Badi King.
This is going to Kerala government.
You know, Kerala they respect Badi very much, that Onam festival.
They will send police and they will arrest me.
You tell, Vamana came, God came in the form of Vamana and suppressed Badi.
Then you can present discussion.
But God became his gatekeeper. But at the same time suppressed. That is what you asked.
You asked it in third person.
You asked it in first person.
Swami, if God came in the human form, then by the grace of that God,
I know that he is the God. Then that time justice should be considered or not?
See, whatever God did, it can never become injustice.
It can appear as injustice to you because of your ignorance, your lack of sharp analysis.
Just now I explained, Govinda has hugged Krishna.
It is not injustice. Because human action will not be fruit.
Whenever you do sin, you know in the present law also,
the person who kills somebody will be given less punishment.
The person who planned the killing will get more punishment.
That SI who planned the killing of Indira Gandhi, he was given more punishment.
And the actual two people who killed, there was a proposal that they should be given lifelong imprisonment.
There was argument in the court. Because the law says,
you see, I want to kill you. I gave some money to some two rowdies.
They don't have intention to kill you.
I have intention to kill you. I gave the money to them.
They killed you. Since they don't have intention to kill you, they will be given life imprisonment.
Since I had intention to kill you, I will be hanged to death.
Intention brings higher punishment. That is in the present law also.
So whatever the action, the action we perform, the intention and the direction is very important.
Intention is important.
So he says Vyasa was asked to produce children with the wives of his brother.
Why all died? It is a royal dynasty. The kingdom must have hails.
The mother Satyavati ordered Sej Vyasa.
Just like artificial insemination, fertility labs.
Same thing, that was, experimental equipment was not there. They were doing that.
Sej Vyasa did not get anything.
Because his intention was not there. Did he by himself,
Mother, brother's wives died, so let me produce.
He did not request. Satyavati.
Satyavati called her and ordered him to.
He has no intention. He will not get anything.
Then our children should be free with knowledge.
Because intention is related to awareness.
And action is related to body. All these things.
Inert things.
Inert thing cannot give fruit.
This is inert stand. Can it appreciate my knowledge?
And put a garland in my neck? No?
It cannot give fruit. It is inert. You have awareness.
So you can appreciate my knowledge and put a garland in my neck. Is it not?
So, sankalpa alone decides the fruit.
Not the karma.
Even though karma is done, it is akarma.
If the action is done by the inert thing, it is not action at all.
Akarma is a karma.
If awareness in the case of awareness, even though you have not done the physical action,
but mentally you are thinking that action, you get the sin.
Awareness is responsible for the fruit.
Not the inert matter, but the inert energy.
Swami, one more question.
So intention gives the fruit, Swami.
In the case of Karna helping Duryodhana, maybe the intention of Karna is good only to help.
But Duryodhana is bad, so why does the seed come to the fruit?
You see, one rupee coin has fallen in the drainage.
You are trying to pick it up, wash it, put some scent.
All these things are waste because Karna is a demon.
He is a demon who came through Surya into the womb of Kunti.
You see, he is a raksha-sa by birth.
That is why he joined with the raksha-sa.
Kauravas are demons. All the Kauravas were demons.
Demon joined with demons. Demon did not join with Pandavas.
Even he knows that he is the son of Kunti, then also he did not like to come to Pandavas.
Even though he knows, he told, I know.
When Krishna took him away and told, you are the son of Kunti, why don't you come to Pandavas side?
He said, I know that I am the son of Kunti, but I cannot leave Duryodhana.
That is his samskara, demon samskara.
He was the person who suggested to Duryodhana to remove the shade of Draupadi.
He gave the advice. You see Bharatam.
He was the person who told Duryodhana to invite Draupadi to sit on his lap.
He suggested.
He told to Duryodhana. He told her also.
See actually Pandavas are his brothers.
He told to Draupadi that, already you have married five.
What is wrong with sixth?
You married Duryodhana.
He told to. See, can a human being knowing that they are his blood brothers,
blood brothers, is not?
Will any human being say this sentence to Draupadi?
He told.
She is defeated. She is our servant.
We have right to remove her sarees.
Whether she wears a saree or not, how does it matter?
He suggested.
See, he got the quality of charity.
Dhanam. Giving practical sacrifice.
That dhanam he got because he stayed in the globe of sun for a long time.
Sun is the best donor.
When he comes, he gives the life energy to all living beings.
Without expending anything in return.
That charity quality is highest in sun.
Because he was associated with sun for a long time, he got that quality from sun.
Since he got that one quality, do we excuse all other demonic qualities?
Suppose somebody is gold ballast.
He steals some money from some house, some gold jewels.
Should he be arrested or not?
He is a gold ballast.
Karna cannot be excused.
Okay.
Six.
If anybody wants to ask questions, you can ask.
Swamiji, how we can...
Let her ask.
Swamiji, how...
You.
Namaskaram Swami.
I have a long-lasting question in my mind for several years.
In this gigantic universe, our earth planet is very minute.
What is the significance, existence of human beings and doing karma?
Is there any profit or loss to the universe?
Suppose I rush back the same question to you.
Take another different example.
JNP University is established.
Some students are studying there.
Lecturers are coming, teaching the lessons.
They are doing practicals.
Then examinations are coming.
Examiners are coming and conducting tests, examinations.
Then they are passing.
Somebody failing.
Somebody passing with happiness.
Somebody failing and committing suicide also sometimes.
So, what is the use of all this?
To get jobs.
Okay, to get jobs, what is the use?
See, the thing is, a systematic system was established by God.
He created the souls.
But at the same time, He established a perfect, regular system.
If you find any fault in His system, you can ask.
But why all this?
Why all this means?
You see, somebody, you have a lot of money.
You have started a college.
With good intention only you started the college.
You have appointed very good staff.
Very good laboratories and equipment you have set up.
No injustice is done anywhere in the administration of the college.
Students are admitted.
They are studying, taking degrees, getting jobs.
So, in this story, the why has no answer at the end.
Why they are studying? To get jobs.
Why they are doing jobs?
To earn something for eating and for...
Why should they eat?
No answer.
Somewhere, this why will have no answer in the end.
But everywhere, you can put the question,
Why He has appointed good lecturers?
He has appointed good lecturers because the college which you have established should run on perfect justice.
See, you cannot say that somebody's...
All the students passed with good results.
But somebody committed suicide because they have not studied well.
Suppose, if his father files a case on you in the court.
Since you started the college, my son got admitted.
And since he failed, he committed suicide.
Had he not started this college, my son would have not died.
My son would have not lost his life.
If he attacks like that, will he...
Suppose, you have given the electricity to all the houses.
My son put his finger there.
Had you not invented this electricity, all the lamps, it would have been alright.
Since you have... suppose, the electricity department will file a case.
How many people are using the electricity?
How many are benefited?
What about them?
You have started a college for some engagement.
To engage yourself in some work without sitting idle.
Now, this father of the boy says,
Because of your engagement in the work, should my son die?
I may have my engagement, my entertainment, my engagement in the work is a secondary thing.
Had I done any mistake in running the college, then I am responsible to answer.
I did not do any mistake.
Staff were best, equipment were best, laboratories were best, conducting the examinations were perfectly correct.
But in spite of all this, why should you start the college?
Since you will be idle, you have no work, then it will bore you.
That is why he has started this college.
And that led to the death of my son.
He committed suicide.
Had you not started college, you would have not committed.
That is not the thing. That is not the answer.
God created this universe for his entertainment.
That Veda says,
Veda itself says that.
But that is only secondary thing.
He created and he is running the whole world with perfect administration.
Nothing, you may think this here injustice happened.
You don't know the whole story of the Bhaidraud.
You are seeing the jailer hanging him.
And you become angry, this is injustice.
Those two fellows have killed 60 people.
That scene you have not seen.
Only you have seen this scene.
So everywhere God's administration is perfect,
because of your partial knowledge, partial awareness of the situation, you may criticize God.
But if you see the whole scene,
present, past and future, all that you can see, the administration is perfect, alright.
His entertainment, entertaining the world may be a secondary thing.
Along with it, if something is enjoyed, it doesn't affect the priority thing.
Suppose you have gone to present a paper in Bombay IIT.
So you have presented the paper, very well, appreciated everything.
While coming back, they have given you some money.
With that money you have purchased a sari for your wife.
You have gone to Bombay to purchase a sari for your wife.
That is only secondary thing.
It does not contradict the priority thing.
You have gone to the IIT, you have presented the paper, all people appreciated.
That is the priority thing.
You can criticize about that.
But while coming to home, you went to shop, you purchased a saree.
Why government has given money?
Only for your charges.
Why should you purchase a saree?
Even if I purchase a saree, I give the private work.
Very good. That is no fault to it.
So therefore, if you go on speaking like that, why has no answer at the end?
Because you continuously will be going.
It appears as if you see, for his entertainment,
we shall be in pain, we shall suffer.
That fellow, if he has no entertainment, let him sleep.
If he is still awake, he will let him sleep.
Then in Ashram, if he is still awake, he will get up.
Four months only.
What about the rest eight months?
So anything more? Anybody?
Padanamaskaram Swami.
Swami, while discussing with Satvika and Kishoranna, we got one question, Swami.
Sometimes in the service of God, even if we do our effort,
if expected output may not come, it causes lot of pain.
How to overcome this, Swami?
You see, even in the service of God, if you are getting like that,
it means definitely there is ignorance in you.
Only due to your ignorance, you are feeling like that.
See, the omnipotent, omniscient God, in His service, if you are getting like this,
then what about the human service and human circumstances?
There may be fault in human. You are working in a hospital.
There is some management. The management may do wrong.
You may get pain. Some injustice may happen. There is possibility there.
But you are telling directly to God, in His service,
I am not getting expectation, and I am pained by that.
That means definitely that is your ignorance only.
Your pain is meaningless. Your idea is wrong.
Nothing, you see, there cannot be darkness in the sun.
There cannot be darkness in the sunlight.
In His administration, nothing is there.
Suppose you have got your pain. It may be like this also.
You might have prayed to somebody in God's service in your dream.
And actually you have to get lot of pain.
God is giving only little pain because you are doing service to Him.
Like that it may happen.
So you should not doubt God under any circumstances.
That you make a rigid rule.
If there is some pain, something, you also asked one question recently.
Brahmanas are having the knowledge.
Then is it not injustice done to other castes? You asked that.
See, some Malayalee department was there.
The Malayalee department is given duty by the government
to speak about malaria and to take precautions to prevent malaria.
Everywhere they should take mic and they should preach to the public.
Suppose you say this responsibility is with Malayalee department only.
Government has shown partiality to Malayalee department.
And all of us are, injustice happened to us.
What they are doing? They are taking mic and telling everything to everyone.
See what Brahmanas are doing?
They are preaching the spiritual knowledge to public from the beginning.
They have not kept that secret in their house and getting benefits.
Then your question is meaningful.
But the Brahmana is expected is given duty by God for botha, for prachara, jnana prachara.
That is his duty.
The malaria department is given some literature.
At that time itself you are telling, our literature is with you.
So you will take all those case in your house.
Public or not?
Injustice is done to public.
No, no, no. They are taking that conflict.
They read at least one night. That night they should read.
Yesterday morning they are coming into the streets.
Yesterday night you kept in your house only.
What about the last?
Yesterday night itself you took the care in your house while reading the literature.
Yesterday night I did not take care.
Because today part of the leader.
Then our malaria department will commit suicide.
Yesterday I will commit suicide.
And nothing else can be done.
So similarly, don't misunderstand everything.
When you understand, take some time, give some time and you understand it properly.
Especially in spiritual side there will be no injustice.
If you do sin, the punishment will be given after some time.
If I do the sin, on the spot itself I will die.
I will vomit the blood and die on the spot itself.
For you it will take some time.
So the brahmanas were given that literature to propagate in the public.
And everybody knows the information. Whoever practices it will get the result.
They are not kept in their house.
And used only for their families and houses.
Because Gyanaprakara is the duty of the brahmanas.
And to protect the justice from injustice through wars, through fighting, is the duty given to Kshatriyas.
And for Vaishyas the propagation distribution of the item to all areas.
One item may be produced in one region.
It should be distributed to all the regions.
That is the duty given to Vaishyas.
And production of the very serious grains is given to Sudras.
All are very important. All the four castes are equal.
All the four professions are noble.
Where is the question of difference?
Difference is there because of difference.
Somebody should be given that duty.
Somebody should be given this duty.
Probability is to somebody.
Treating all are equal.
You do this, you do this, you do this, you do this.
They are even using. Why you are giving that duty to him?
I mean somebody I have to give.
Probability is equal.
Yes, probability theory.
Theory of probability.
It is random.
So therefore, everything you see, he is producing by agriculture.
Is it not distributed to all public?
Yes.
He is distributing all the products in all regions.
Is it not benefiting all people?
Yes.
And that fellow is fighting injustice anywhere, found.
Is it not safety for all the people?
Yes.
And he is propagating the spiritual knowledge for all the people.
Is it not benefiting all the people?
Yes.
You are not following it.
And you are doing in Malay department.
See they say, they are telling clearly, don't put open water.
If you put open water, the mosquitoes will breed.
Always cover the water with some plate or some cloth.
That he is telling to everybody.
Due to laziness, you have not put the plate.
And the mosquito breeding was there.
And you got malaria.
You fellows, Malay department fellows.
They have already given instructions in the mike.
Every caste is given a duty which benefits all the public.
See they say, Ashotra is born from the feet.
See from the feet, river Ganga is born.
Which removes all the sins.
Even Brahmana cannot do that.
To remove the sins, he has to perform long puja.
But Ganga river if you take dip, all the sins go.
That is born from the feet.
And she is the sister of Nidra.
They are brothers of Ganga.
This is not.
Feet means suppose somebody crush the feet, will he be able to walk?
So difference, only difference exists.
But not low and high.
Hierarchy is not there.
All this nonsense developed from the beginning of Kali age.
Because Kali is spirits.
Introduces squirrels.
Kali wants squirrels.
Kali wants hatred.
Kali wants fighting.
That is influence of Kali.
Hello.
What is the difference between Dattapareesha, Vishnopareesha and Rudraparesha?
No, Brahmapareesha, Vishnopareesha and Rudraparesha.
These we are called as Dattapareesha.
Tell me.
What is the difference you want?
Is it not?
See Brahmapareesha means that if God appears and you ask some boon from him, he expects
some boon from him.
He will not give the boon, he will just disappear.
Then will you still maintain the devotion on God, Brahma?
Out of hundred, ninety will go away.
In Brahmapareesha, in the quarter, twenty will go away.
That is quarter examination.
In the half yearly middle Parishah, that is Vishnopareesha, you ask God appears, you ask
him some hundred rupees.
Then he says, okay, I will give you, then he will search your pockets.
If some ten rupees is there, then you will get the boon.
Not giving, but taking away our also, ours also.
Then will you still love God?
That is Vishnopareesha.
And Rudraparesha is the final annual test.
In Rudraparesha, he will give you some hundred rupees, then he will give you some hundred
rupees.
Then he will give you some hundred rupees.
And if you pass Rudra Paritasha also, then God Darta will appear and will merge in you
and will make you as God Darta.
He will never allow the source to merge in him.
He merges in the source.
That is in your name, in your name, your life, your identity is maintained.
And you will do the, you will get all the powers of God Darta.
That is more, you know.
Instead of you will disappear and dissolve in him.
Then he does something.
The credit goes to God Darta only, not to you.
Is it not?
So the salvation given by Darta is very peculiar, different.
That is the soul will dissolve in, the God will dissolve in the soul and the soul will not dissolve in the God.
That is the final fruit given by Darta.
Okay?
Okay Swami. One more question Swami.
Jesus was crucified among two thieves on either side.
Any message in that being crucified with two thieves?
You see, if you take their statements, they are completely different from the statements of Jesus.
See somebody, one says that when you go there, you also remember me.
See it is a question like bribing.
They both are not, see when Jesus was crucified, he never gave any statement harassing anybody.
He never begged those people to show kindness on his life.
He never begged.
He did not say anything.
Then he said, Oh God, they don't know what they are doing.
You please excuse them.
That is the level of Jesus.
The level of the two thieves are not that.
So he is showing the difference of the human incarnation and ordinary people.
One may be like an ordinary devotee who asked him to remember him when he sits on the lap of the father.
He may be treated as a worldly devotee, aspiring for some aspiration.
And other fellow is a worldly man, other person, prisoner.
And the statements given by Jesus, the behavior shown by Jesus, proves that he is the human incarnation.
And the other two are, one is a devotee, another is an ordinary soul.
Okay?
Okay, I am in.
Okay, Swami. Thank you. Thank you.
Okay, okay.
Okay.
Where is your wife?
I am the wife of your husband.
Okay.
I have already told that concept.
In Veda, it is told,
The so-called males in the world are not only females, but are also wives of God.
That is in Veda.
Because husband means bharta.
Bharta means,
Who maintains.
God is maintaining all the souls.
Bharya means,
Who is maintained.
So, not in other sense, but in this sense you have to take that word.
Not only female, but also the wife of God.
That means the male ego should be left.
Male ego should not be shown on the wife.
For that, that statement is given.
So, Ramakrishna Paramahamsa, when he went to Burundavana,
For one month, he was wearing shari and putting jewels like gotga.
So, all souls before God,
Before God,
They should not have any trace of ego.
That is the meaning of the statement.
You are misusing that here.
I am using correct sense.
Sarva Bharta.
Even you use that,
The sense is not the relationship of husband and wife.
That is not the sense.
Vibharti is the bharta.
He who maintains, the substratum,
The electronic instrument is on the table.
That table is bharta and that is bharia.
Bharya means that is maintained.
This is maintaining.
Maintainer is bharta.
Maintained article, maintained item is bharya.
In that sense, all souls, even the so called males,
Are females and wives of God.
But that means even the males are maintained by God only.
They are not maintaining angels.
Because of God only.
Everything, all the entire creation is maintained by God.
Then males are also included in the creation.
Thank you.
Namaskaram.