Swami, shall we start, Swami?
So then, shall we start, Swami?
Today we are celebrating Guru Purnima.
Say, Guru is nothing but to remove our ignorance.
Say, Lord Datta, he is the Guru Datta.
He always comes, incarnate himself to remove our ignorance.
And our beloved Sri Ratta Swami is incarnation of Lord Datta and came down in human form to give excellent knowledge and remove our ignorance and showing in, taking us in a right direction and a right path.
And we know in spirituality we have lot of questions and lot of priesthood knowledge was also there.
And Swami is correlated all the spiritual knowledge.
Like today we have said Guru Purnima is Vyarava Vedavyasa birthday.
Our Swami is correlated even all the Vedas, Vedas, Upanishads and Bhagavad Gita, Prasthana Trin, not only that He correlated even the modern science up to this point.
Swami is giving excellent spiritual knowledge.
Only He incarnate to remove our ignorance.
Datta Swami is none other than the Lord Datta himself.
And we are so fortunate that today directly we are meeting, we are talking and we are seeing our contemporary human incarnation.
It's so fortune that we can directly get all clarifications, all our doubts.
He will clear all our doubts.
If everybody can ask whatever they got doubts, Swami will clear all our doubts.
I pray Swami please remove our ignorance and give your blessings to all of us.
So anybody have questions can ask, can question Swami, Swami can answer all the questions.
Shall I ask? Yes, yes.
Aday Namaskaram Swami, this is Bharat Krishna.
Swami my question is generally it is said that it will take millions of janmas to achieve the spiritual goal which is to please God, that is the human incarnation of God.
Why it takes so much time Swami?
See in Bhagavad Gita there is one verse,
Adhajeenam nishchayatam nishcham vamanyaseyamrutam
That means, if you are not in the spiritual world,
In Bhagavad Gita there is one verse,
Adhajeenam nishchayatam nishcham vamanyaseyamrutam
That means, this soul, this individual soul dies in the night in deep sleep.
And in the morning when he wakes, he is reborn.
So one day in one life.
So many dasas, many days, not years, not lives, not even years.
Just one day morning he is born, night he dies in deep sleep.
Therefore, if you take the right interpretation,
It means only after many days only you can get the salvation. That's all.
So here, the question is, why it takes so much time?
The verse in Bhagavad Gita says,
This soul dies in deep sleep every day.
And in the morning when he wakes, he is reborn.
So one day in one life.
So many dasas means many days.
So there is nothing to worry about.
Thank you Swami. Excellent.
Swamiji, I have one question Swamiji.
With respect to having expectation of the fruit of a work that has been performed,
should not be there to avoid tension.
But how can a work be done without having an intention of doing it for a particular fruit?
That I am not able to understand.
So you see, you can have intention for some fruit.
You are working for it. To achieve the fruit, you are doing work.
That much initial intention is alright.
But during the entire course of work, if you always think about the fruit only,
then your energy will be exhausted in thinking about the fruit and energy is limited always.
And that limited energy is spent in thinking about the fruit, in the excitation only.
Then there will be no energy to do the work.
Then you will not get the fruit.
Initially you can have some fixation of fruit.
Later on you should not think about the fruit.
If you go on thinking due to attraction towards fruit,
if you go on thinking and worrying about the fruit,
all your energy will be spent in that worry, in that excitation,
in thinking about the fruit only, then energy will be over.
Energy is limited.
Then energy is not remaining to do the work.
You will stop doing work in the middle itself.
And if the work is not completed, you will not get the fruit.
Therefore you should not worry about the fruit.
Once you start the work, you should not worry about the fruit.
He is asking,
the person who thinks about the fruit should keep working.
How can he do the work if he thinks about the fruit?
The first thing he should do is to decide that he is doing this work for the fruit.
But if he thinks only about the fruit while working,
he will not get the fruit.
If he thinks only about the fruit, he will get excited.
With this, he will spend his energy.
Then energy will not remain.
You will not be able to do the work in the middle.
If you do not do the work, you will not get the fruit.
If you work completely, you will not get the fruit.
Therefore, if you think only about the fruit,
you will not be able to do the work while thinking about the excitation.
Thank you, Swamiji.
Okay.
Swamiji, hello.
Dhanamaskaram, Swamiji.
Namaste.
Can I ask a question?
Yes.
Swamiji, without any mistake, someone cheated on us.
So how do we take care of that person without any mistakes that people cheat on us?
Then how do we think about it in that way?
Is it our karma that that person has to teach us some lessons in our life?
You see, if you want to escape cheating, you should have precaution.
Prevention is better than cure.
Okay, already somebody cheated and you underwent some loss.
Now, the next necessary thing is to take care in the future.
Take it as a lesson.
First, if you go to the background, it is only due to past karma.
You might have cheated that fellow in the past birth, and now he is cheating you.
So that is a retarded case, the mutual canceling.
So you cannot take action against him.
If it is a retarded case, you cannot do anything against that.
If it is a fresh case, you have not cheated him in the previous birth.
Freshly he has cheated you now in this birth.
In that case, you live to God and don't have any revenge attitude, vengeance.
Don't show vengeance.
Keep silent and live to God and pray God.
If it is a fresh case, God will certainly punish him, not only punish him.
See, if he is punished, your loss will not be compensated.
So you should not think about his punishment.
Punishing him, punishment means to reform him.
By punishment, God is going to reform that sinner.
It is only for reformation, not for vengeance, not for revenge.
Even if he is punished, how your vengeance goes?
Because your loss is a loss, your loss is not compensated.
What do you get by punishing him?
Nothing you will get. Your loss is there.
So when you are thinking with revenge, vengeance attitude, your health is spoiled.
Previous loss plus more loss.
So therefore, don't develop any revenge attitude.
Keep silent, pray God and live the result to God.
Now God will certainly take action because the case is now in the court of God.
God is the ruler of this entire world on any day.
If the revenge is not taken, if the fellow is not punished,
it is a black mark on the administration of God.
He will go and worry, why should you worry about his administration?
Moreover, if he is punished, you are not getting your loss compensated.
Moreover, another third point is that if you show revenge, vengeance attitude,
revenge attitude on that fellow, what happens you know?
For your revenge attitude, you will be also punished by God.
God will punish him, but extra you will be also punished for your revengeful attitude.
Best example, you know Draupadi, injustice was done to Draupadi.
The Kauravas dragged her chavi and tried to make her naked.
So Kauravas are sinners. Draupadi is the victim. Kauravas are the criminals.
Krishna has decided, God has decided to punish Kauravas.
But meanwhile, Draupadi showed a lot of revenge attitude towards Kauravas.
She was always weeping and crying and telling Bhima and Arjuna that
unless you kill Dushyasana, bring blood, I will not fold my heel.
Like that, she was always expressing vengeance, revenge attitude towards the sinners.
Anyway, for the sin of Kauravas, Kauravas were killed by Krishna.
Arjuna and Pandavas are only just nominal, namke vastha people, that's all.
Actually the killer is only Krishna.
Krishna killed Kauravas and Shri Suntara.
Draupadi was always showing vengeance, revenge attitude.
What happened you know, in the last day, all the five sons of Draupadi were also killed by Ashwatham.
What is the use of winning the war?
If she won the war, her sons will become the kings.
Then only it has meaning.
So along with Kauravas, her five sons were killed and no son of Draupadi became the king.
The kingdom which was won by the war.
So therefore, if it is a retarded case, if you have treated him in the previous birth,
now he has treated, cancels, no more punishment for the criminals.
If it is not retarded case, if it is a fresh case, that is you have not treated him in the previous birth,
but now he has treated you, then also you don't show any revenge attitude towards your enemy.
You just pray God, asking him to do whatever he feels is right.
Whatever is to be done, you please do.
You leave everything to God and pray God.
Then God will give you compensation for your loss, plus God will punish them.
But God will punish them not for revenge, your revenge or he has no revenge.
He punishes them only for reformation, to reform the criminal.
That is the aim of punishment.
And moreover, if he is punished and if God is not compensating your loss,
what is the use of punishing your criminals?
What compensation you got? You got no compensation.
So by punishing your enemy, you will not get any compensation.
So don't think of punishing your enemy.
Leave it to God. God will punish your enemy and will also,
because you did not show any revenge attitude, he will compensate your loss.
That is the real benefit.
Otherwise, if you show the attitude of vengeance, what happens?
Your enemy will be punished, if it is not a retards case.
But you will not be compensated by God.
And by punishing your enemy, did you get compensation? Nothing.
So, wisdom wise people, what they do, they never make any revengeful attitude.
They will never show revengeful attitude.
They keep silent, leaving everything to the hands of God.
This is your administration. You do whatever you want to do.
It is the administration of God.
If that fellow is really a criminal and if that criminal is not punished,
the black mark will come to God.
Because it is God's administration that is going on everywhere,
not these governments which are present.
These are only superficial governments.
But the actual final judgement is given by God and things will happen as per that judgement.
So, that is the best thing.
I will tell you in Telugu.
Good.
Someone asked me what should I do?
Should I fight with the people who are shooting me?
Or should I sit quietly?
This is the question that Mr. Ali asked.
What I am saying is, this could have been a retort case.
In the previous life, you might have cheated him.
But in this life, he has cheated you.
We thought it was a retort case.
You could have punished him.
Because you did what he did and he cancelled the meeting.
So, there would have been no further action.
That is the proof for that.
You would have been hurt then.
The second thing is, it could have been a fresh case, not a retort case.
You didn't cheat him.
But he cheated you in this life.
If you cheat him in this life,
you would have been angry and would have said,
You would have said,
You should be punished with your life.
You would have been hurt.
The problem here is,
If you punish him,
will your loss be fulfilled?
Will you get compensation for your loss?
You will get it, right?
What is your profit if he punishes you?
So, you are trying to escape from him.
You will not get any profit if he punishes you.
You will not get any loss if you escape.
You will not get any new loss.
So, we thought about this.
What decision should we take?
We should leave the Lord.
We should pray to the Lord for your peace of mind.
Not for his loss.
We should leave the Lord.
Because the Lord is the King.
He is the final.
The government is the only one.
The underlying government is the only one.
The only government is the Lord.
Jesus Christ says,
The kingdom of the universe is near.
The kingdom of the universe is the government of God.
That is always stable.
That is the only thing that is active.
It is the only thing that is active.
So, if you leave it like that,
what will God do? He will punish you.
Then why will he punish you?
You did not want to be punished, right?
Why will he punish you?
Because the Lord is not only the one who punishes you,
but also the one who changes your mind.
He is the one who reformates you.
He will punish you for reformation.
So, how can you punish him?
If you say, you are a fool, he will punish you.
Then,
I can say, I am useless even if I get punished.
You should be calm.
You should be praying to God.
You should not be punished by force.
You should be calm.
God will make up for your loss.
If you stay like this,
the story of Draupadi is the story of Draupadi.
Draupadi was insulted for a day.
She was wearing a dress and was wearing a turban.
So, for that, the Christians went and killed them.
They killed the Christians and they brought them back.
Otherwise, they would have killed the other people.
The Ajayandu
asks Yasun
in the Drona Parvam.
Yasun asks Yasun, if you want to die, say,
Grandpa,
when I fight daily, I will throw arrows.
The enemy will die.
But when I shoot arrows,
before my arrow reaches him,
a great man will take Trishala and kill him.
After he dies, my arrow will reach him.
The great man will ask,
the Lord said,
you prayed for the holy weapon,
but the Lord is killing your enemies every day.
The great man is killing them.
That is why
God will punish them.
He will definitely punish them.
You should not be punished by force.
I am talking about the Drona Parvam.
They have done a great sin.
The great man decided to kill the Christians and he killed them.
Why did the great man keep his mouth open?
He kept his mouth open.
When will you kill the Christians?
When will you kill them?
He kept his mouth open.
When the Christians put their mouth open,
they killed the Christians.
He kept his mouth open.
He was not at peace.
He killed five children.
Last day, Ashwathamang.
He came to the temple.
He killed five children.
These children should rule the world.
What is the value of killing?
All these children died.
That is why you will be punished.
But the mouth is open.
The mouth is open.
Be at peace.
This is the kingdom of God.
This is the administration.
If the one who committed the sin does not repent,
the next black mouth God will come.
Why will you come, Ashwathamang?
The next black mouth God will come.
He will keep his mouth open.
He is the real worry.
He should be worried.
Not you.
You should be worried about the black mouth God.
When you are at peace,
you should not seek punishment.
You should be at peace.
You should not seek punishment.
I have cheated him in my past life.
He cheated me in my future life.
He is the real worry.
This is true.
He said,
You are at peace.
You shouldn't seek punishment.
You owe God compensation
and let them suffer.
Now let me know what you want.
Also,
you'll lose the power
That is the responsibility of a God.
To save the one who has done wrong, to save the one who has sinned, that is the responsibility of a God.
He is the one who is the rightful owner. He will fulfill it.
You are the one who is the rightful owner. If you fulfill it, then what is left?
So, if you stay in the middle of it and do not increase the value of the money,
and pray to God in peace, then he will take it.
Then the case will be yours.
There is no case against you.
If you stay like that, he will compensate for the loss you have caused.
That is the benefit.
If you do not compensate, then you will be punished.
That is the question he asked.
Question from the audience.
Swami, you have taken the Shorastra avatar, right?
I have not.
I have taken the Dattva avatar.
I have taken this Kasai avatar and taken this avatar.
I used to wear a laban shirt and be a professor in college.
I have taken this avatar and taken this avatar.
In the book of Saraswati Swami,
There are many such small avatars, right?
Yogi Raja, Atrivaludu.
Yes, I have written it in Spanish. Tell me.
What is the meaning of that?
See, tell me the question and the time will be enough.
You can meet me anytime and I will give you the answer.
Give me the time.
Swami, my question is,
You are a physics expert, right?
Sir, physics is a subject, right? I will tell you the answer.
The heat.
In the heat, light or in the matter of matter, there is a doubt.
I do not understand.
He will tell you the answer.
I have told you the subject of the magadha of the phoebe.
She is not a doubt.
Swami ji, the human incarnation of God is compared to sugar and the devotee is compared to ant.
You mean Ramakrishna.
Ramakrishna.
Swami, in other context, even a prostitute also can be compared as sugar and the...
Prostitute is sugar.
Even the Shiva is a sex disease.
Syphilis, daniriyan, parapsak, even the ears.
Ok, tell me.
That is...
What is your doubt?
Even in prostitution, they also sing good songs to the Lord.
Now, I am saying that the gopikas are sages in previous births.
So, in the last birth, they will sacrifice their bodies to the Lord.
In the same inni vrutthi case, if a prostitute wants to get liberated, why...
When her prostitute is in that state, why should she use that money for her work? Why should she not get liberated?
See...
In the last birth, someone killed a goat.
The goat was killed and made a baby.
The goat was skinned, beaten and given to the Brahmin.
Is the baby going to die?
The goat was killed, skinned, beaten and donated to the Brahmin.
Oh my God, I thought my baby was dead.
So, prostitution is a sin.
Now, prostitution is a sin.
I am singing good songs to the Lord.
I am a sinner.
If you give that money to the prostitute, she will be saved.
We earn according to our religion.
Our family members also earn.
They come up.
This is the book of Injustice.
Injustice is the law of the universe.
You earned 10 rupees in justice.
Injustice is a
I earned 10 rupees in justice.
We earn according to our religion.
Why do we earn?
Because we earn for our children.
That is the only desire.
It does not happen.
They get destroyed.
Later,
until that money is lost,
they get destroyed.
So,
it is the attraction of the village.
If you look at the clothes,
if you look at the beauty,
you get attracted to the beauty.
The money is attracted to the beauty.
But,
it gets destroyed when it is lost.
If they get destroyed,
everyone gets destroyed.
Because,
the people who get the money,
get destroyed.
So,
we should not earn unjustly.
If we earn in a way,
it is right.
If we give it to God,
if God always saves it,
if God always accepts it,
then you are unjust from then onwards.
Realization, repentance and non-repetition are the same.
If these three are combined, it is reformation.
You have realized that this is a sin.
Repentance,
this sin is a sin.
Non-repetition,
you should not repeat the sin of the mother.
Then,
all the sins that are done behind,
are all cancer.
All cancer.
If you do three,
some people do realization, repentance and non-repetition.
But if you do the four,
and if you do the five,
then you can forgive in the evening.
If you do the six,
then you can forgive in the morning.
If you do the seven,
is it free?
If you do the eight,
you can forgive in the evening.
You should not do the eight,
and you will not eat the food.
You should not eat the food.
Is it clean?
Is it pure?
That is the principle.
It works.
Non-repetition of this in
realization.
You know it is a sin,
you are suffering for it.
You understand it
as if you are not being amazed.
After this,
that sin will come.
What are those sins?
Everything will be forgotten.
Everything.
All the sins
that were done previously.
Not all sins,
but those types of sins.
You have committed a theft,
you know it,
you have done non-repetition
without committing a theft.
If you want to steal,
you get cancer.
But there are other types
of sins,
right?
If you do that type of non-repetition,
you get cancer.
If you don't do
anything,
you get cancer.
So,
the non-repetition
is not done again.
It is life load.
When it is realized,
the whole process is completed.
But what are they doing?
Many are going to
realization, repentance,
confession.
The boy who did it in the morning,
science and confession.
The other day, the confession.
That is not it.
What is the answer?
The sin of being cancelled
because of confession.
Non-repetition.
If you don't do it again,
all those types of sins will be cancelled.
The other day,
The logic behind it is
that all the sins are being cancelled.
The intention behind the sin
is to perform the reformation.
When you perform the reformation,
why do you need more sins?
When you have already
realized it,
you don't need to do it again.
That is the logic.
Punishment is only for reformation
and punishment is not for vengeance.
Punishment is not for vengeance.
Reformation is not for revenge.
Someone was killed.
He is being tortured.
Do you know why?
Because he is not killing the other person.
If someone is really not killing the other person,
what is the use of torturing him?
How can we waste time?
Torture?
That is the logic.
Okay.
Namaste, Swamiji.
Namaste.
I am from Mumbai.
Yes, yes. Tell me.
On this auspicious Guru Gurunima day,
I offer my sincere gratitude
and a total prostrated pranam
to your divine rotorspeak.
Okay, thank you.
And to my appeal,
guiding my weak and undist mind,
you had said that I assured you
you will succeed in getting your problem cured.
Your words came true in all aspects of my mental health.
Let us begin.
I have been telling you recently on my query
on my better health condition,
you have said you will get my guidance
as you proceed in the work.
But I also wanted to go in the direction of God,
which is a permanent solution.
And there you have also said
you will have to face a lot of strain
in working for God.
Kindly elaborate further on this
as I am ready to go to any extent to prove
that I could come close to you,
come close to you, Swamiji, in my life.
Okay, very good.
You are blessed.
Thank you, Swamiji.
You will get proper guidance.
You need not do too much work also.
You need not do.
You can do as per your health permits,
as per your capacity permits,
as per your energy permits.
That is sufficient for God.
Whether you are interested in doing
practical work for my case or not,
that is only the test of God.
He is not in need of any work from us.
If there is any need,
then the fellow will think,
if he does more work,
my work will be more done.
Not like that.
God is only testing
whether you are only theoretical
or practical.
Also, practical is the proof for theory.
Practical devotion is the proof
for theoretical devotion.
Theoretical devotion without practical devotion
is a false love.
It is not true love.
Unless you sacrifice something practically,
unless you do some service practically,
service means sacrifice of energy,
physical energy,
sacrifice of fruit of work.
That is first is Karma Sanyasa,
another is Karma Parachyaka.
Both these together are called as Karma Yoga.
Karma Yoga is the proof for Bhagya Yoga.
Bhakti Yoga is theoretical devotion.
Karma Yoga is practical devotion.
Practical devotion is the proof for
the truth of theoretical devotion.
Whether your bhakti is real or false,
that Karma Yoga decides.
The practical devotion decides.
Very simply,
guess, you may sing so many songs,
shed tears,
then God will say,
He will also sing songs on you,
He will also shed tears,
or if you want a boon from that,
oh, you get more sweeter voice,
He will let you get more tears from your eyes.
So for theoretical devotion, theoretical boon.
For practical devotion, practical boon.
So actually in our India,
we are very, very much, very highly
experts in theoretical devotion.
That is why once somebody asked,
Swami Vivekananda looked at this Thay
and asked God,
why in our country, in India,
so much devotion, so much knowledge is there,
but still why they are poor?
Somebody has put that question to me,
directed that question to me.
Then I told, yes,
our India is very great in knowledge,
spiritual knowledge, Gnana Yoga,
and experts in Bhakti Yoga,
singing songs on God,
but will not give a single rupee for a poor fellow.
In practical devotion, they are zero.
In foreign countries,
they are least Gnana Yoga,
very least Bhakti Yoga,
but they do charity, practical charity,
they do much.
That is why they are rich countries,
our country is poor country.
That is the reason.
We are experts in theoretical devotion,
theoretical knowledge.
So for theoretical knowledge and theoretical devotion,
God gives theoretical boons.
Let your knowledge increase more,
let your knowledge increase more,
let your brain become more intelligent,
let your voice become more sweet,
let more tears come while you sing,
like your audience also,
shed tears,
more tears.
So theoretical devotion means theoretical boons.
In whatever way you approach me,
I am your God.
So, I am your God.
If you approach me,
I approach you again by the same way.
If you come by bus, I will come by bus.
If you come by train, I will come by train.
If you come by airplane, I will come by airplane.
In letter of the scripture,
I am just your reflection,
your mirror reflection.
Whatever way you approach,
if you show your intelligence,
I will show lot of intelligence.
It will give you fruit.
If you show innocence,
I will be also innocent.
Hedonism asked that he should not be killed by such things,
either day or night, or inside or outside,
or weapons with awareness or without awareness,
like that, so many conditions.
All the conditions he has broken,
and for every condition he neutralized,
and killed Hedonism.
He should not belong to a single race,
man or animal,
Deva or Asura,
Gantara, Narasimha,
neither man nor animal,
neither inside nor outside,
at the center of the gate,
it is neither outside nor inside,
nor on the floor nor on the sky,
he has put on his laps,
neither floor nor on the sky.
Like that, for every thing he has shown,
what the exception.
He is very intelligent.
You show your intelligence to other human beings,
but when you come before God,
kindly shut up your intelligence.
Be innocent.
Be frank with him.
Don't show your intelligence.
If he enters into the game,
your address will not be there.
So don't play with him.
Be true.
Be frank, be sincere,
be truthful.
Then you will get something from him.
If you show intelligence,
finish him.
So you see Sudama,
how innocent he is.
He gave three handful of parched rice,
did not ask anything.
He came back to his house,
he never thought about anything,
he retired from him,
and when he came back to his house,
unimaginable wealth he gave.
Because he is innocent.
See, his wife sent him to Krishna
to get something.
He was so poor.
But the fellow did not speak anything.
Krishna asked him to stay for four days,
he stayed for four days,
then he told, I will go to my home.
Yes, he said, go.
Like that he told.
He did not give any one rupee.
When he was washing his feet,
when he came,
there was a thorn in his feet.
He was not having the sensitivity of that thorn.
He was not having any chappals to his feet.
So when he came and when he was washing,
all his eight vices were pouring water,
and he was washing his feet,
and the thorn hit his palm.
Then he plucked out.
He plucked out and from that time onwards,
there was no need of the eight vices to pour water
with gold vessels,
because
from that time onwards,
he washed his feet with his tears.
Water was not necessary.
Satchakrishna,
he doesn't have any chappals.
Now he is going back to his home.
Hey, Sudama, wait.
At least take this ten rupees.
Purchase some second-hand chappals.
He should give it or not?
No, not a single rupee he gave.
He also started again working with barefoot feet.
And as long as he was going to his house,
Krishna, he has the miraculous powers.
He is observing the mind of Sudama.
There were somewhere,
that fellow,
he has wrapped,
seeing my feet,
while washing the feet.
And when I am coming,
one rupee he has not given.
He acted like an Hollywood hero.
Acted?
Unseen that thought.
Now one rupee he has not given.
Like that, whether he is saying in his mind,
he was observing his mind.
He has got the capacity, you know.
He is omni-quotient.
He is not a person.
He is a person.
Till he went near to his house,
the house remained like that only.
Just when he is approaching his house,
he bent his head and he is approaching his house.
Then suddenly, now he will not scold Krishna.
He decided, Krishna.
At that moment,
he changed his mind.
The house became a big palace.
It was not done immediately.
He waited there,
till he reached in the house,
whether he will scold me once or not.
If he had his scolding once,
his house will remain as that also.
Swamiji, Namaskaram Swamiji.
Few minutes back, you answered about
not having the revengeable attitude
when someone cheats us.
So, let us take one example.
If someone cheats me by stealing some money,
so, if I file a complaint in police,
is that also a revengeable attitude
or is it justified?
No, that is not a revengeable attitude
because you don't know
whether it is a retarded case or a fresh case.
So, there,
when I have taken the case of Draupadi,
that situation is completely different.
She cannot fight by filing
a case in court
because it was the king,
Duryodhana was the king.
Is it not?
So, what I tell is
the case,
the circumstances
in which you cannot do anything,
any reaction,
you are unable to take any reaction.
You are unable to take any reaction.
Very big fellow.
You cannot fight with him.
You see, compare
Draupadi and Duryodhana.
They are very powerful.
She is ready.
She cannot fight.
So, that is the circumstances I told.
If there is anything
that you can do,
you do it. But sometimes,
you cannot fight.
That fellow may be very big,
rowdy.
He may say, if you go to
police station or court,
you will be finished.
Then you will not go.
Then what to do?
Okay?
Thank you.
One more question.
That same question, Swamiji.
But we will be having
like a pain or like hurt
or pain in the heart.
Like a pain or like hurt
like that person has
did these things with me.
So, we were getting suffering
from those pain,
not that person who has
done the cheating and all.
So...
See, if you can
fight, you fight out.
If you are cheated by somebody,
and if there is provision for you
to fight,
you fight.
That is not wrong.
Suppose there is no provision
to fight. Suppose that
fellow is very powerful.
You are not so much powerful.
Suppose he says, if you fight, I will
kill you.
And we all are encouraged also, you
found that he is capable of
doing that.
In those occupations,
I told like this.
But if you are able
to fight,
and you are not
fighting, you are sitting like Arjuna
in the Kurukshetra war,
what Krishna told to Arjuna?
You fight.
See, you have got some army,
they have got some army.
He came to the war
to fight.
Then you fight.
He did not say, go back.
He was going to throw
on the bar,
and keep silent.
I was dead.
He did not tell like that.
Hello?
Yes, Amiji.
See, if you have permission to fight,
if you have chance to fight,
you must fight.
If there is no such provision,
if the enemy is very strong,
and suppose
threatens that he will kill you,
and on enquiry
he also found that he is capable
of such thing,
then you
approach God.
Not about Amiji, then?
What about then
in relations kind of?
Like how?
There we can't fight, like
if that person did this with us, then?
What relation you mean?
When he has cheated you,
when he has cheated you,
what type of relationship you can have with him?
No relation.
You should cut off all relations.
He is a cheat.
He has cheated you.
If you maintain all relations,
he again cheat you.
See, when you are
cooking the food rice,
you take one
grain and press it
whether it is cooked or not.
Is it not?
So one example is sufficient.
The entire rice is represented by that one grain.
His entire rice is represented by that one example.
Padi Namaskaram Swami.
Yes.
Is wanting liberation an act of aspiration
though it is not worldly?
As long as God is a fruit at the end,
then it is not a sin.
It is a sin.
As long as God is a fruit at the end,
we would be aspiring to reach Him.
So how should we approach God, Swami?
He is wanting
liberation
and act of aspiration
though it is not worldly.
As long as God is the fruit
at the end, we would be aspiring
to reach Him.
So how should we approach God, Swami?
See, you are talking about liberation
and reaching God.
Is it not?
Attachment to God
and detachment from
liberation means detachment
from worldly bonds.
Detachment from worldly
and attachment to God.
Here they are very much related.
Unless you attach
to God, you
cannot liberate yourself from
the variety.
If you want to have some
detachment from something,
you must attach
yourself to some other thing.
Then the detachment
will be spontaneous.
Automatically you will be detached.
Suppose you are sitting in a cinema
hall. See in the cinema,
you are very much
absorbed in the cinema.
You are very much attached to the cinema
story.
Now, the mosquitoes
are biting.
The blood bugs of the seat,
they are also biting.
You need not try to
liberate from mosquitoes and
blood bugs.
If you are absorbed in the cinema,
you will not mind these bites.
You are automatically liberated.
So, the attachment to
God must be
the cause for your detachment
from the world.
Without attachment to
God, if you liberate
from the world, it is the
biggest foolishness.
See,
I am drinking divine nectar,
amrutam.
I am drinking it.
Then spontaneously,
automatically, I want to drink
coffee.
Before the taste of amrutam,
this is nothing.
I hate it.
I don't take it.
Because of the taste of
amrutam.
Neither you drink amrutam,
nor you drink coffee.
You are a fool.
At least if amrutam is not
available, let me drink coffee.
Something I have to drink.
That drinking habit is there
for this tongue
and for the mind.
The mind always wants to drink
something. The mind always wants
to attach itself to something.
That is its
inherent nature.
So, now
you are not attaching yourself to God.
You are also not
attaching yourself to the world.
Will mind keep silent?
In two, three days,
you will have double
attachment to the world.
It is not prerequisite.
To drink divine nectar,
there is no precondition
that you should not drink coffee.
It is not a pre-stipulated
condition.
If you drink divine nectar,
due to that taste,
you automatically,
spontaneously leave drinking coffee.
Such type of detachment
you should get.
Without drinking the divine nectar,
you want to
newly coffee.
Two days, three days you will leave.
On fourth day you will drink a bucket of coffee.
It is
impossible.
Detachment from the world
without attachment to God
is impossible
and also foolish
and also useless.
What is the use?
At least if that is not available,
you enjoy this.
You lose this.
You don't
enjoy that.
So, Moksha, liberation from the worldly bonds,
is defined as
the liberation from
the worldly bonds
due to the attachment to God.
That is very important.
You must attach to God.
Then you should not try for
liberation from the worldly bonds.
Auto-naturally it takes place.
It is a spontaneous by-product.
For which you need to try at all.
It is a natural
phenomenon. Naturally you will get
detachment.
You drink divine nectar.
Naturally you will be detached from coffee.
Such type of liberation
is Moksha.
You are not drinking divine nectar.
You are not attached to God.
You are leaving
the worldly bonds.
That is not Moksha at all.
It is only foolishness.
People leave the house and go to the forest
and
sit there in meditation.
They will be thinking only worldly things.
Then they will run back.
They will come back to home.
They will not come back. They will run.
Run that home.
Run that to the home.
In the death ritual
they put rice in a mud pot
and they put
some koudang in.
Raw rice and put koudang in it.
They take the dead body along
with that pot
and cremate it.
Regarding that one death ritual
Swamiji.
The other one is with
the tarpanam.
It is the conteration tarpanam.
They have black sesame seeds
and the raw rice
mixed.
We put in water and we do
tarpanam and that
rice and seeds should be thrown
in a place where it can't be
grown back.
Instruction has been given by
elders at my home.
The third one is
having a haven
for samitadhan, for brahmacharis
who have completed their
tarpanam.
After every sandhyamandhanam
samitadhanam is also
instructed to do for brahmacharis.
These three
rituals, clarifications
I need Swamiji further.
You see
there is one
shloka in dhama shastra
in the scripture itself.
When there is a contradiction between
smruthi and
shruti
then there is
a contradiction between
smruthi and
shruti.